If the
もし
,​
,​
Academia Sinica's November Knowledge Feast Lectures began.
中央研究院の11月の知識の饗宴講義が始まりました。
Wang Hansheng, vice president, hosted for us.
副社長の王漢生氏が私たちのために司会を務めてくれました。
Director Li Jie, Dear Distinguished Guests, Dear Friends
リー・ジエ監督、ご来賓の皆様、親愛なる友人の皆様
That's because Vice President Chen
それは陳副総統だからです。
have my agent
私の代理人を雇ってください
Dr. Mingzhe is the Agricultural Biotechnology Research Center of our hospital
明哲博士は当院の農業バイオテクノロジー研究センターです。
Special Forces researcher and director are the agricultural and biological center
特殊部隊の研究者とディレクターは農業および生物学のセンターです
He graduated from the Biology Department of Tunghai University in 1976
彼は 1976 年に東海大学生物学部を卒業しました。
In 1978, he studied genetics at the University of Elva
1978年にエルバ大学で遺伝学を学んだ
After getting a Ph.D. in 1983
1983年に博士号を取得後
Postdoctoral research at Harvard University
ハーバード大学での博士研究員
In 1988, he returned to the Biology Department of the University of Elva to teach
1988 年に、彼はエルバ大学の生物学部に戻り、教えました。
Later served as a professor of biology at the school
その後、同校で生物学の教授を務めた
and Director of the Center for Comparative Genomes
比較ゲノムセンター所長
After 20 years at the University of Elva
エルバ大学での20年間を経て
in January 2008
2008年1月に
Apply back to our hospital as the Agricultural Biotechnology Center
農業バイオテクノロジーセンターとして当院に再度申請してください
Special Forces Researcher and Director
特殊部隊研究員兼ディレクター
And served as the forward-looking translation of the hospital
病院の将来を見据えた翻訳としての役割を果たしました
Chief host of the Agricultural Cooperative Program
農協プログラムチーフホスト
Director Shi's expertise is in applied molecular biology
Shi 所長の専門分野は応用分子生物学です。
and comparative genomics methods
および比較ゲノミクス手法
To explore the function of genes in plants and vitamins
植物やビタミンの遺伝子の機能を調査する
and the mechanism of message transmission
そしてメッセージ伝達の仕組み
His current focus is on plant
現在注目しているのは植物です
Molecular Mechanism of Flooding Response
洪水応答の分子機構
There is also the impact of environmental changes on Taiwan's downturn
台湾景気低迷には環境変化の影響もある
And the color and fragrance of Phalaenopsis orchid
そして胡蝶蘭の色と香り
gene regulatory network
遺伝子制御ネットワーク
He also integrates cross-school teams
彼は学校を超えたチームも統合します
Construction of Taiwan Agricultural Genome Database
台湾農業ゲノムデータベースの構築
According to my observation, after Director Shi came back in 2008
私の観察によると、施所長が2008年に復帰してからは、
He played great organization
彼は素晴らしい組織力を発揮した
follow the power of mobilization
動員の力に従う
In fact, Taiwan's related research fields
実は台湾の関連研究分野は、
quite different
全く違う
Form many cross-school teams
学校を越えて多くのチームを結成する
and lead many large projects
多くの大規模プロジェクトを主導
Also on behalf of Congress to promote Taiwan
議会を代表して台湾を宣伝することも
with the EU in the field of agricultural biotechnology
農業バイオテクノロジー分野におけるEUとの提携
Science and Technology Exchange and Cooperation
科学技術交流・協力
And it is also the agricultural policy of Academia Sinica in 102 years
そしてそれは102年ぶりの中央研究院の農業政策でもある
Planning committee with scientific and technological research proposals
科学技術研究提案企画委員会
The topic he is going to talk about today is
彼が今日話そうとしているテーマは
Sustainable Development of Taiwan's Agriculture
台湾農業の持続可能な発展
we welcome him with warm applause
私たちは温かい拍手で彼を歓迎します
Thank you, Vice President Wang, Dean Li
王副院長、李学部長、ありがとうございました。
Secretary-General Wu and distinguished guests
呉事務総長と来賓
that's great to have the chance today
今日はこの機会があって嬉しいです
Let's exchange opinions with you
皆さんと意見交換しましょう
That is, I am actually a wedding paper creature.
実は私は結婚式の紙の生き物なのです
The agricultural policy towards Taiwan is 2008
2008年の対台湾農業政策
I have a chance when I come back to Taiwan
台湾に戻ったらチャンスがある
That's how we got to know Taiwan
こうして私たちは台湾を知りました
The situation of agricultural development
農業開発の状況
that has some personal thoughts
それは個人的な考えがあります
that's great to have the chance today
今日はこの機会があって嬉しいです
I can discuss with you
相談できます
then i will put my speech on the wedding schedule
それから私のスピーチを結婚式のスケジュールに載せます
Three parts of the big column marriage
大列婚程三部分
the first is
一つ目は
Discuss issues related to Taiwan's current agricultural policy
台湾の現在の農業政策に関する問題について話し合う
Then in the middle I'll bring up
それから真ん中で私は持ち出します
means I go
私が行くという意味です
Do you think there are any ways we can improve these agricultural policies
こうした農業政策を改善する方法はあると思いますか
can solve these problems
これらの問題を解決できる
and then the last part
そして最後の部分
Can you hear me?
私の声が聞こえますか？
I'll get to the last part
最後の部分に行きます
In fact, the real problem we have to face
実際、私たちが直面しなければならない本当の問題は、
That is the impact of global warming on Taiwan's agriculture
それは地球温暖化が台湾の農業に及ぼす影響だ
what impact will it have
どのような影響があるでしょうか
Then how do we solve it
ではどうやって解決すればいいのか
That...
それか...
a little louder
もう少し大きな声で
help me fix it
それを直すのを手伝ってください
seems to be broken
壊れているようです
May I
いいですか
ok
Ok
we should be...
我々はする必要があります...
ok sorry
すみません
ok then we can start
わかりました、それでは始めましょう
The Academia Sinica regularly
中央研究院は定期的に
That is to say, it is important to our country
つまり、我が国にとって重要なのです
technology or social issues
テクノロジーや社会問題
make suggestions
提案をします
That is usually the dean
それは通常学部長です
to form a committee
委員会を結成する
Hiring experts inside and outside the hospital
病院内外の専門家を雇用する
Then do the so-called policy white paper
次に、いわゆる政策白書が登場します。
In 102, Academia Sinica published a book called
そして102年、中央研究院は次のような本を出版しました。
"Agricultural Policy Building Books with Science and Technology"
『科学技術で農業政策を構築する本』
The book is really thin
本は本当に薄いです
If you are interested
もし興味があれば
It can be exposed from the network of our Academia Sinica
中央研究院のネットワークから公開される可能性があります
But this book is thin
しかし、この本はとても薄いですが、
Among them, only our Taiwan is currently
その中で、現在私たちの台湾だけが
Structural Problems in "Agriculture Facing"
「農業が直面する」構造的問題
There are six questions in total
質問は全部で6つあります
But one of them refers to
しかし、そのうちの1つが言及しているのは、
Our old farmer's allowance has become a political bargaining chip in the election
私たちの古い農民の手当が選挙の政治的交渉材料になった
As a result, the book was published
その結果、本が出版されました
The next day the newspaper published a lot of news
翌日の新聞にはたくさんのニュースが掲載されました
I won't talk about most of the content
内容のほとんどについては話しません
Most of the scholars of Academia Sinica are hiding in the laboratory
中央研究院の学者のほとんどが研究室に隠れている
I don't know the sufferings of the people
国民の苦しみは分からない
This is a relatively mild criticism.
これは比較的穏やかな批判です。
Zhang Huaguan, the magistrate of Chiayi County, is
嘉義県知事の張華関氏は、
Xi Xiaolong is big big today
習小龍は今日も大きくなりました
He has one last sentence not in it
彼には最後に一文が入っていない
i saw him on tv saying
彼がテレビで言ってるのを見ました
peasants will riot
農民が暴動を起こすだろう
So let me start with this question
それではこの質問から始めましょう
i watch tv in america
私はアメリカでテレビを見ます
One of my favorites is called
私のお気に入りの 1 つは
BioNumber
バイオナンバー
Just use trees to explain the problem
木を使って問題を説明するだけです
So I'm going to start giving you guys
それで、私はあなたたちに与え始めます
talk about some trees
いくつかの木について話す
This old farmer is the first one to look forward to history today
この老農場主は今日の歴史を楽しみにしている最初の人です
In the 84th year of the Republic of China
民国84年
It's the so-called our government's economy took off at that time
それはいわゆる私たちの政府の経済がその時に始まったものです
Plus the WTO issue
さらにWTO問題も
So there will be imported food
だから輸入食品もあるだろう
So our government will
したがって、私たちの政府は、
So it's kind of like rewarding our old farmers
つまり、これは古い農家に褒美を与えるようなものです
So he set up a so-called welfare allowance for elderly farmers
そこで彼は、高齢の農民のためのいわゆる福祉手当を創設した。
But a law called the Battle Form
でもバトルフォームという法則
The so-called combat regulations are temporary and transitional
いわゆる戦闘規制は一時的かつ過渡的なものである
In the future there will be a more permanent legislation to take care of our old farmers
将来的には、高齢の農民を世話するためのより恒久的な法律が制定されるでしょう。
In the 1987 of the Republic of China
1987年に中華民国で
It is said that it will be included in the so-called national pension system
いわゆる国民年金の中に組み込まれるということです。
In July 1996, the legislation was actually passed
1996 年 7 月にこの法案は実際に可決されました。
Once the legislation is passed, it will be implemented in January 1997
この法案が可決されれば、1997 年 1 月に施行される予定です。
Then the implementation of this announcement is to bring the old farmer's pension into the right track of the national pension system
そして、この告示の実施は、旧農業者年金を国民年金制度の正しい軌道に乗せることである。
But in July 1997
しかし1997年7月に
Our Legislative Yuan Passed Old Farmer's Pension to Restore the Old System
私たちの立法院は旧制度を回復するために老農民年金を可決した
through the National Pension
国民年金を通じて
So it's back to the Battle Form Regulations
バトルフォームレギュレーションの話に戻ります
This battle is up to now
この戦いはここまで
Before July 103
103 年 7 月以前
I'll tell you what happens after July
7月以降のことはまたお知らせします
Before 7 months old farmers today's application qualifications
生後7か月以内の農業者 本日の応募資格
Yes, as long as you have been insured for agricultural insurance for 6 months
はい、農業保険に6か月加入していれば可能です。
If you are over 65 years old, you can receive it for life
65歳以上なら生涯受け取れる
At the beginning of today, the old farmer paid 3,000 yuan a month
今日の初め、老農民は月に3000元を支払った
The Democratic Progressive Party increased the price to 5,000 yuan, and the KMT increased the price to 7,000 yuan a month
民進党は月5000元、国民党は月7000元に値上げ
So when you are 64 and a half years old, you buy rural insurance
つまり、64歳半になったら田舎の保険に加入することになります。
From the age of 65, you will receive 7,000 yuan a month for life
65歳からは生涯月7000元を受け取る
Later, after Chen Baoji became the chairman of the Council of Agriculture
その後、陳宝吉が農業評議会主席に就任した後、
He tried to improve the old farmer's pension
彼は老農民年金を改善しようとした
So he introduced a bill and it didn't pass
それで彼は法案を提出したが通過しなかった
So then it became a thing
それでそれは事になりました
He just passed a person named Laolong last year
彼は去年老龍を追い抜いたばかりだ
Amendment to Article 3 of the Provisional Regulations on Old Dragon Allowance
古龍手当暫定条例第３条の改正
just one amendment
たった一つの修正
That is to say, if you have received the old dragon's allowance before the practice, it will be the same as usual.
つまり、練習前に古龍のお手当をもらっていれば、いつもと同じになります。
You after July 103
103 年 7 月以降のあなた
You need 15 years of rural insurance
15年間の田舎の保険が必要です
So he extended six months to 15 years
そこで彼は6か月を15年に延長した
To be able to spend the thousand-amount Laolong subsidy of 7,000 yuan
千の老龍補助金7,000元を使えるようになる
Then you feed six months for 15 years
その後、6か月で15年間養われます
half price
先領半額
Wait until the seniority reaches 15 years before spending the thousand amount
年功が 15 年に達するまで待ってから、1,000 ドルを使いましょう
So this solves half of the problem
これで問題の半分は解決します
Because these have been received
これらは受け取ったので、
You can see how big our country's burden is
我が国の負担がいかに大きいかがわかります
This is me from our Republic of China
これは中華民国の私です
Annual budget book Council of Agriculture's budget
年間予算簿 COAの予算
you can go
行ってもいい
to that Taipei network
あの台北ネットワークに
every year for the past ten years
過去10年間毎年
you put it in
あなたがそれを入れました
This is the Council of Agriculture
こちらは農業委員会です
you don't count it the one
あなたはそれをその1とは考えていません
reserve fund
積立金
this is its total budget
これが総予算です
almost every year
ほぼ毎年
100 billion up and down
一千億上下
look at everyone
みんなを見て
How much does the old farmer's annuity cost each year
農業老人年金は毎年いくらかかりますか
50 billion or so
五百億上下
So the COA's budget
COAの予算は
at least half
少なくとも半分
Spend directly on the old farmer's annuity
農業従事者年金に直接支出する
But it's more than that
しかしそれ以上のものです
look at everyone
みんなを見て
there is an item
アイテムがあります
COAG Development Lecture Subsidy
COAG開発講座助成金
This talk about subsidy is not about
この話は補助金のことではありません
is a subsidy
補助金です
List of agricultural losses in Taiwan
台湾における農業損失のリスト
then any
それなら何でも
Special for any township need
あらゆる町のニーズに応える特別な
What's up with the poker bit
ポーカービットはどうしたの
it's all in there
すべてはそこにある
look at everyone
みんなを見て
From 16 billion to 39.2 billion
160億から392億へ
So the subsidy from the Council of Agriculture
そこで農業委員会からの補助金が
about 80 percent a year
年間約80パーセント
used for subsidies
補助金に使われる
If you only have 20 billion
200億しかないなら
No matter how good your agricultural policy is
どんなに優れた農業政策を行っていたとしても、
you can never do things
あなたは決して物事を行うことはできません
If it's just a matter of the old farmer's pension
老人農業者年金だけなら
Then maybe if we change the old farmer's pension regulations
それから、古い農業者年金規定を変えたらどうかと思います。
that can be solved
それは解決できる
look at
見る
we have other questions
他にも質問があります
the first is
一つ目は
Our Agricultural Pruning Questions
農業の剪定に関する質問
You probably often see it in the newspapers
新聞でもよく目にするのではないでしょうか
But in fact, the original benefit was not only root cultivation
しかし実は、本来の恩恵は根を育てることだけではありませんでした。
that now becomes
それは今になる
Look at the area from our water to Taiwan's seeds now
私たちの水から台湾の種子までの領域を今見てください。
About 250,000 hectares
約25万ヘクタール
Our paddy fields are about 220,000 hectares
私たちの水田面積は約22万ヘクタールです
That is to say, about half and half
つまり半分半分くらい
Only half of the farmland is in use
農地の半分しか利用されていない
half in pruning
半分剪定中
We subsidize root trimming every year
毎年根切り補助を行っています
Are you in that old farmer's pension?
あなたはその老人の農業者年金に入っていますか？
another 10 billion
あと100億
It's in the Jiang subsidy
それは江補助金の中にあります
There are other sub-items
他にもサブアイテムがあります
A total of 10 billion in subsidy each year
年間総額100億の補助金
Well, if you have these figures, these subsidies are really subsidizing farmers, that's fine.
そうですね、この数字があれば、この補助金は本当に農家に補助金を出している、それでいいのです。
Everyone, take a look, this is the top five subsidies in the country published by the United Daily News
皆さん、見てください、これはユナイテッド・デイリー・ニュースが発表した国内の補助金トップ5です。
The farmland they own, the money that has been subsidized by Xiu Geun for the past five years
彼らが所有する農地、過去5年間Xiu Geunから補助金を受けてきた資金
These people are not farmers, these people are investing in farmland
これらの人々は農民ではありません、これらの人々は農地に投資しています
Therefore, many subsidies from our government have not actually reached the hands of farmers.
したがって、政府からの補助金の多くは実際には農家の手に届いていません。
but in the hands of some speculative class
しかし投機的な階級の手に渡った
Well, if you look at the source of the original root repair policy
さて、元のルート修復ポリシーのソースを見てみると、
Actually there are two parts
実は2つの部分があります
In the 73rd year of the Republic of China, he actually wanted to teach farmers to cultivate their roots.
民国 73 年、彼は実際に農民に根を耕すことを教えたいと考えていました。
That transfer means
その移転とは、
accept government grants
政府の補助金を受け入れる
fallow that year
その年は休閑
The right to use your farmland
農地を使用する権利
to the Council of Agriculture
農業委員会へ
integrated by COA
COAにより統合
distributed to other yeoman
他のヨーマンに配布
Or go to the so-called small landlords
あるいは、いわゆる小規模地主のところに行きます。
The concept of small landlords and big electricity farmers
小規模地主と大規模電力農家の概念
This is how young people can be encouraged to grow chairs
これが若者に椅子を育てるよう奨励する方法です
In fact, this idea has existed since the Republic of China in 1973
実際、このアイデアは 1973 年から存在していました。
But this law entered the Legislative Yuan
しかし、この法律は立法院に提出された
fallow still
まだ休閑
transfer to see
乗り換えて見る
so
それで
31 years later
31年後
we still have only fallow
まだ休閑地しかない
not converted
変換されていない
Guys, don't think your fields are fallow
皆さん、自分の畑が休耕地だと思わないでください
put it there
そこにそれを置きます
It will not affect
影響はありません
nothing
なし
after fallow
畑が休耕した後
if you don't take care of it
気を付けないと
that place will
その場所は
There will be pet pests and diseases, rodents
ペットの害虫や病気、げっ歯類が発生します
anything
何でも来る
So what you made is that farmland
あなたが作ったのはその農地です
you do not need
いらないよ
So pruning for too long will destroy your field
剪定が長すぎると畑がダメになってしまいます
And where are you pruning our excess power?
そして、私たちの過剰な電力をどこで削減しているのでしょうか？
cause social problems
社会問題を引き起こす
Because if there is no place to use the strong power in the countryside
田舎に強い力を発揮する場所がなかったら
Naturally, social problems will arise
当然社会問題も起きる
When we were discussing this white paper,
私たちがこのホワイトペーパーについて議論していたとき、
Some committee members said that Taiwan is like kidney dialysis.
一部の委員は、台湾は腎臓透析のようなものであると述べた
It's because he listens to underground radio commercials in rural areas
田舎のアングララジオCMを聞いているからだ。
just took a lot of medicine
ちょうどたくさんの薬を飲んだばかりです
Another Mark Six lottery may also be redundant in rural areas
別のマークシックス宝くじも地方では余剰になる可能性がある
But this is actually Starly who didn’t do it carefully
でもこれ、実はスターリーが慎重にやらなかったんです
so just listen
だから聞いてください
But it will cause rural police officers and rural social problems
しかし、それは地方の警察官と地方の社会問題を引き起こすでしょう
absolutely no problem
全く問題ありません
if that's all
それだけなら
created yet another law
また別の法律を作った
continuous evil
継続的な悪
Because in 1989
だって1989年に
Our organization has made an amendment called the Agricultural Flower Regulations
私たちの組織は、農業用花卉規則と呼ばれる改正を行いました。
This is in my opinion the worst agricultural policy ever
私の意見では、これは史上最悪の農業政策です
because it's the first
それは最初だから
It widens farmland acquisition restrictions
農地取得制限を拡大する
In the past, it was not very profitable for you to buy and sell farmland.
以前は、農地を売買してもあまり利益が得られませんでした。
You must be qualified as a farmer
農業従事者の資格が必要です
You will pass it on to your descendants who will also be farmers
あなたはそれを農民になるあなたの子孫に伝えます
Therefore, the inheritance of agricultural land is always under the hands of farmers
したがって、農地の相続は常に農民の手に委ねられています。
And it changed
そしてそれは変わりました
natural person can take over the farmland
自然人は農地を引き継ぐことができる
Natural persons are our personal inheritance of farmland
自然人は私たちの農地の個人的な相続財産です
If a farmer wants to sell land, you can buy it
農家が土地を売りたいなら、あなたはそれを買うことができます
Natural people have to bear
自然人は耐えなければならない
Second, it allows agribusiness corporations
第二に、アグリビジネス法人を許可します。
Conditional inheritance of farmland
農地の条件相続
The company you call yourself an agribusiness
あなたが自らをアグリビジネスと呼んでいる会社
then you can buy land
そうすれば土地を買えるよ
So it is equal to the free sale of agricultural land
つまり農地を無償で売却するのと同じことになる
The worst thing is
最悪のことは
Before Xiuhua, you have to buy and sell farmland
華を修復する前に農地を売買する必要があります
You are not allowed to cut it into small pieces
小さく切ることは禁止されています
You must have more than five hectares
5ヘクタール以上の土地を所有している必要があります
but this bill
しかしこの法案
it revised it down from five hectares to 0.25 hectares
面積を5ヘクタールから0.25ヘクタールに引き下げた。
So you can start mowing your farmland now
今すぐ農地の草刈りを始めることができます
cut a little
少し切る
0.25 hectares is about 750 square meters
0.25ヘクタールは約750平方メートルです
Section 18 of the Farm Digging Regulations Amendment
農場採掘規則改正第 18 条
I added this
これを追加しました
in it this law
その中でこの法律
Those who acquire farmland for 1.4 billion yuan are called farmers
14億元で農地を取得した人を農民と呼ぶ
Actually no matter how old you are
実は何歳になっても
As long as you have this land before
以前この土地を持っていた限り
You don't care about the size of the farmland
農地の広さは気にしない
you can change the farmhouse
農家を変えることができます
The idea of ​​the farmhouse is you because you farm
農家のアイデアはあなたが農業をするからです
So you build on top of your farmland
つまり、農地の上に建物を建てるのです
call definition
呼び出し定義
but after january 89 you acquire farm land
しかし89年1月以降は農地を取得する
They are called Xinnong
彼らは新農と呼ばれています
Need to obtain more than 0.25 hectares
0.25ヘクタール以上の土地を取得する必要がある
And it will take two years before the construction of agricultural works
農作業の建設までには2年かかります
This looks like a good policy
これは良い政策のように思えます
That is to say, you can't be anywhere
つまり、あなたはどこにもいないのです
You can't build a house right after you sell the farmland
農地を売ったらすぐに家は建てられない
but you have countermeasures
でも対策はあるよ
We Taiwanese must have countermeasures
私たち台湾人は対抗策を持たなければなりません
this is the worst
これは最悪です
It will be built after two years
2年後には建てられます
Why
なぜ
because you're the one who buys and sells land
土地を売買するのはあなただから
If he wants to sell it to others to build a house
家を建てるために他人に売りたい場合
Then if people have to wait two years
では、人々が2年待たなければならないとしたら、
Of course he won't come to buy
もちろん買いに来ないよ
so they figured out
それで彼らは理解した
Still Farmland Goushe Weird Phenomena
依然農地苟社怪象
It covers a small probably
おそらく小さな部分をカバーします
I think it's really like a kennel
まさに犬小屋みたいな感じです
Everyone, if you go to Yilan, you will see a kennel
皆さん、宜蘭に行ったら犬小屋を見ますよ
I think many people probably don't know why they cover this
なぜこれを取り上げたのか分からない人も多いと思います
because it can sell land
土地が売れるから
If you buy this person
この人を買うなら
people of this land
この土地の人々
because it already has
すでにあるので
This is called a ready-made farmhouse
これは既製の農家と呼ばれます
it can apply for extension
延長を申請できる
It can be expanded to the villa it wants
ご希望のヴィラに拡張可能です
so
それで
The front looks as if it could be prevented
フロントは防げそうな気がする
It is the misuse of farmland that has become this
こうなったのは農地の悪用だ
Then everyone, go through the Beiyi Highway
それでは皆さん、北宜公路を通ってください
you can see
見ることができます
It's called a kind of house, a kind of kennel
それは一種の家、一種の犬小屋と呼ばれています
one by one like this
こうやって一つ一つ
these are all
これらはすべてです
In preparation for the subdivision of farmland
農地の分譲の準備をする
Land for sale as a villa
別荘として販売中の土地
The consequences of these agricultural policies
こうした農業政策の影響
Amendment to Agrochemical Regulations
農薬規制の改正
It trades farmland subdivision restrictions
農地の分譲制限を取引する
There are also qualifications for agricultural property construction
農地建設の資格もある
So good farmland is lost quickly
優良な農地はすぐに失われる
The production environment is also polluted
生産環境も汚染される
and the worst
そして最悪の
You probably don't know the definition of our peasant
あなたはおそらく私たちの農民の定義を知らないでしょう
what is a farmer
農民とは何ですか
My hunch is that you must have farmed
私の予感では、あなたは農業をしていたに違いない
farming, right?
農業ですよね？
But the census we do
しかし、私たちが行う国勢調査は
Every five years we do something called the agricultural census
私たちは5年ごとに農業国勢調査と呼ばれる調査を行っています。
if i tell you
私があなたに言ったら
From the ninety-nine years of the Republic of China
中華民国99年以降
From ninety-four to ninety-nine
九十四歳から九十九歳まで
Our farm households increase by one percent
私たちの農家の世帯数は​​ 1 パーセント増加しました
do you believe it
あなたはそれを信じていますか
If you believe me there is a house on Mars that will sell you
私の言うことを信じてくれるなら、火星にあなたを売ってくれる家がある
that peaceful age of our farmers
私たちの農民たちの平和な時代
Sixty-seven-year-old real Bunon's frontier
67歳の本物のブノンのフロンティア
Therefore, in the past 10 or 20 years, there has been absolutely no increase in farmers in Taiwan.
そのため、ここ10年、20年、台湾では農民が全く増えていません。
Look at the census from that time, I think it's an underestimate
当時の国勢調査を見てください、過小評価だと思います
40% of the so-called qualified farmers have never worked in the fields all their lives
いわゆる資格のある農業従事者の 40% は、生涯畑で働いたことがない
not engaged in farming
農業に従事していない
so this
したがって、この
Therefore, if you obtain the qualification as a farmer
そのため、農業者の資格を取得すると、
If both Yilan County and the Council of Agriculture want to restrict
宜蘭県と農業委員会の両方が制限したい場合
The condition for obtaining the qualification as a farmer
農業者資格取得の条件
But it means a lot of resistance
でもそれは大きな抵抗を意味する
come down and listen to my
降りてきて私の話を聞いてください
So now it's 2015
さて、2015年になりました
The organizing committee of Chen Baoji is very determined to do something
陳宝吉組織委員会は何かをするという強い決意を持っています
Including the government of Yilan County
宜蘭県政府を含む
I don't know if they are cooperating
協力してるかどうかは分からない
They are also considering this
彼らもこれを検討している
Use administrative decrees instead of legislators to legislate
立法には議員の代わりに行政命令を使用する
Because of the administrative law, the words of the executive order
行政法のせいで、大統領令の文言は
as long as
に限って
It won't be able to do it directly on the canvas
キャンバス上で直接実行することはできません
So at the beginning of the year
それで年の初めに
That is, the Council of Agriculture revises agricultural land and builds new farmhouses
つまり、農業委員会が農地を見直したり、新しい農家を建てたりするのです。
farmhouse approach
農家のアプローチ
The first one is to restrict farmers to build new
1つ目は、農家が新しい建物を建てることを制限することです。
and buying and selling farmhouses
農家の売買
That is, you must be a farmer in your business
つまり、あなたは農家である必要があります
In case the farmhouse is improperly planted by intermediaries and consortiums
農家が仲介業者やコンソーシアムによって不適切に植えられた場合
But when it comes to the Executive Yuan, it will be amended first.
しかし、行政院に関しては、まず行政院が改正されることになる。
first cut in half
まずは半分にカット
The Executive Yuan has decided that the builders of farmhouses are limited to farmers
行政院は農家の建設者を農民に限定すると決定
this is no problem
これは問題ありません
Because farming law is like this
農法はこうだから
But if the successor doesn't ask you, you will have to practice farming law
ただし、後継者が求めない場合は、農業法を実践する必要があります
Because if you remember the farming method I talked about earlier,
なぜなら、先ほどお話しした農法を思い出していただければ、
It means that the recipient can be a natural person or an agricultural enterprise
受取人は自然人または農業企業である可能性があることを意味します
So the Executive Yuan is
つまり行政院は、
he theoretically stands still
彼は理論的には静止している
He must go to the Legislative Yuan to amend the law
彼は法律を改正するために立法院に行かなければならない
so this is no problem
だからこれは問題ない
So please ask this court to implement the first half first
したがって、この裁判所に前半部分を先に実行するよう依頼してください
Later, the Nonghua Regulations stipulate that Chen Xiuren must be above the agricultural level
その後、農華条例により、陳秀仁は農業レベル以上でなければならないと規定されました。
And property farming more than one year
1年以上の不動産農業と
However, there are agricultural health insurance, health insurance and the third category no longer hold cash
ただし、農業健康保険、健康保険があり、第 3 のカテゴリーは現金を保有しなくなりました。
if you only talk about this
これだけ話すなら
Do not add the latter singular
後者の単数形を追加しないでください
I think it's a good policy
良い政策だと思う
If you are in the Legislative Yuan, you can pass
立法院にいる場合は通過できます
Probably solved more than half of the problem
おそらく問題の半分以上は解決しました
Why
なぜ
look at everyone
みんなを見て
What is the third category of insurance?
3番目の保険カテゴリーは何ですか?
Member of Farmers Association and Water Conservancy Association
農業協会および水利協会の会員
He doesn't limit you to be a farmer
彼はあなたを農民であるとは限定しません
to join these members
このメンバーに加わるには
Also over 15 years old
こちらも15歳以上
A civic approach to agricultural implementation
農業実施に対する市民的アプローチ
So this is a big loophole
つまり、これは大きな抜け穴です
The second is that you have to attend the ceremony
2つ目は式典に出席しなければならないことです
Become a fake class member
偽のクラスメンバーになる
Or over the age of 15 engaged in a job for 1 month
または15歳以上で1ヶ月以上の仕事に従事している方
So you mean to say you join the farmers' meeting
農民会議に参加するということですね
You can become a farmer and buy agricultural insurance
農家になって農業保険に加入できる
This is to buy agricultural insurance and build a farmhouse
これは農業保険に加入して農家を建てることです
So this is a big farmer
これは大きな農家です
There is another way you can become a farmer
農家になる別の方法もあります
That is, you go to participate in the farmer distribution class of the Council of Agriculture
それは、農業委員会の農家配布教室に参加しに行くことです。
Two Issues You Are a Farmer
農家としての 2 つの問題
You can farmer loans
農家融資ができる
Then you can buy agricultural insurance
そうすれば農業保険に加入できる
Then start to receive agricultural subsidies
その後、農業補助金の受け取りを開始します
so we all thought
それで私たちは皆考えました
This was formulated by the Council of Agriculture
これは農業委員会が策定したものです
This is actually just an amendment to an executive order.
これは実際には大統領令の修正にすぎません。
should be no problem
問題ないはずです
But everyone, look at the Apple Daily on October 4
でも皆さん、10月4日の蘋果日報を見てください。
there is
がある
usually executive order
通常行政命令
Legislators have no power to review
議員には審査権はない
this
これ
The vice council organ politely sent it to the Legislative Yuan for future reference
副院機関は今後の参考のために丁重にもこの文書を立法院に送付した。
But after this bill and this amendment are sent to the Legislative Yuan
しかし、この法案と修正案が立法院に送られた後、
There are 18 legislators including Chen Chaomin from Miaoli
苗栗州の陳超民議員ら18人が参加
These eighteen are all legislators of the Kuomintang
この18人は全員国民党の議員である。
Everyone will go, most of them will go
全員が行きます、ほとんどの人が行きます
Accompanying them at the press conference is National Real Estate
記者会見に同行するのはナショナル・リアル・エステート（National Real Estate）
Chairman of the Council
評議会議長
They are against the Council of Agriculture
彼らは農業評議会に反対している
Sending this bill to the Legislative Yuan will change from reference to review
この法案の立法院への送付は付託から審査に変更される
If you know
あなたが知っていれば
Once you're in the legislature and you're under scrutiny, that's bad.
ひとたび立法府にいて監視されると、それは悪いことだ。
the spirit of your original legislation
あなたの元の法律の精神
Probably all of them will be changed. It's a mess.
おそらく全部変更されるでしょう。めちゃくちゃです。
And among the 18 legislators
そして18人の議員の中には
I promise you one or two may not be clear
1 つか 2 つは明確ではないかもしれないことを約束します
What is the New Deal order? What is the legislation of the Legislative Yuan?
ニューディール政策とは何ですか?立法院の法律とは何ですか?
I won't call names
名前は呼びません
But I want you to check the list
でもリストをチェックしてほしい
You'll know these legislators just sign
これらの議員が署名するだけだとわかるでしょう
just come on
さあ来てください
Therefore, the Council of Agriculture is worried that the case will be brought back to the review room
したがって、農業評議会は、この事件が審査室に持ち戻されることを懸念している。
I am also worried that in the face of the adversity of the law amendment
法改正で逆境に陥ることも心配です。
So now our policy is stuck here
したがって、私たちのポリシーはここで行き詰まっています
These six items are what we set out in this white paper
この6項目がこのホワイトペーパーに書かれている内容です
It is about the structural problems that Taiwan’s agriculture is currently facing
台湾の農業が現在直面している構造的な問題についてです
The first is that I have already explained
1つ目は、すでに説明したことです
It is the rapid production of environmental substances in the farmland
農地での環境物質の急速な生成です。
I haven't talked about this yet
このことについてはまだ話していません
The production environment affected by the second long-term root pruning policy
2 回目の長期ルート プルーニング ポリシーの影響を受ける運用環境
Then the Nongjin post is what I just talked about.
それから、農津ポストというのが先ほど申し上げたものでございます。
Then these are unreasonable agricultural regulations
それでは、これは不合理な農業規制です
that this
これは
Council of Agriculture, if you spend more than 80% of your budget on subsidies
農業委員会、予算の 80% 以上を補助金に費やす場合
Of course you don't have money for anything else
もちろん他に使うお金はない
So you can't blame the COA
だからCOAを責めることはできない
Because almost all of his money is in the Legislative Council and he has to do it
なぜなら、彼の資金のほぼすべてが立法評議会にあり、彼はそれを実行しなければならないからです。
Mended must do
修繕しなければならないこと
So his budget is 100 billion since 80 billion is gone
つまり、彼の予算は800億がなくなったので1000億です
So he only has 20 billion a year to take care of our agriculture in Taiwan
つまり、彼が台湾の農業を維持できるのは年間200億ドルだけだ
so there is no way
だから仕方ない
So these five are actually more or less related to our agricultural policy
つまり、これら 5 つは実際には多かれ少なかれ我が国の農業政策に関連しているのです。
what is the solution
解決策は何ですか
There are short-term and long-term short-term solutions
短期的な解決策と長期的な解決策がある
I just said something
私はちょうど何かを言いました
In fact, as long as you really implement the existing laws and regulations
実際、既存の法律や規制を本当に実行している限り、
Let me give you an example of a farmhouse
農家の例を紹介します
certainly
そうです
In the original development regulations, it was the regulations on rural development
当初の開発規制では、農村地域を建設するという規制でした。
Paragraph 3 of Article 3 and Article 18 also provide
第 3 条第 3 項および第 18 条にも次の規定があります。
You are applying for farmhouse qualifications to be directly engaged in agricultural production
農業生産に直接従事するための農家資格を申請しています。
Then it is limited to farmers who do not have their own farmhouses
それから、自前の農家を持たない農家に限定する。
And other farmland must be used for agriculture
そして他の農地は農業に使用しなければなりません
Don't underestimate this executive
この幹部を過小評価しないでください
You can implement this as long as you rely on administrative orders
行政命令に頼る限り実行できる
You execute well and I promise you the farmhouse problem is over.
あなたが正しく行動すれば、農家の問題は終わると約束します。
Why? You're the first to buy or sell
なぜですか? 最初に売買するのはあなたです
To apply for agricultural qualifications, you must directly engage in agricultural production
農業資格を取得するには、農業生産に直接従事する必要があります。
So you just win a review and don't let those fake farmers cover it
つまり、レビューを勝ち取るだけで、偽の農家にそれを取り上げさせないようにすることができます。
That's what the Yilan County Government is going to do.
それが宜蘭県政府のやろうとしていることだ。
The result is to pass this bill again
その結果、この法案は再び可決されることになる
In the past, there were a lot of this
昔はこういうのが多かった
The brokerage of Huangwu went to protest in front of Xianzheng Five
黄武の仲介業者が宣正五前で抗議活動に行った
That is to say, it should not be strictly enforced
つまり、厳密に施行すべきではない
What is the qualification of farmers
農業従事者の資格とは何ですか
But Yilan Constitutional Five is strictly enforced
しかし、宜蘭憲法第五条は厳格に施行されている
So he is going to build a farm now
それで彼は今農場を建設するつもりです
It's less, that is to say, it's 20% slower
少ない、つまり 20% 遅い
speak slowly
ゆっくり話す
So you just have to do your best
だから頑張ればいいだけだよ
You can probably do the first half of the policy
おそらくポリシーの前半は実行できるでしょう
Sale and purchase of farm cooperatives with closed farmland
閉鎖農地を有する農協の売買
The second part you can make living there very uncomfortable
2番目の部分では、そこでの生活が非常に不快になる可能性があります
Because of your other 750 ping you built a house
残りの 750 ピンのおかげで家を建てました
Other than that, you are here to do farming
それ以外は、農業をするためにここにいます
You can't tell me how many fruit trees I planted
私が植えた果樹の数を教えてもらえない
or make some of that paper disaster
あるいは紙の災害を起こしてしまう
then you can
そうすればできます
he regards agriculture as
彼は農業を次のように考えています
This is not legal anymore
これはもう合法ではありません
so two or three months ago
それで2、3ヶ月前に
The vice chairman of the Council of Agriculture is in Yilan
農業評議会の副委員長が宜蘭に滞在
There was a farmhouse that was talked about
話題の農家がありました
He planted a few rows because of him
彼は彼のために数列植えた
he has a farmhouse
彼は農家を持っています
his house is qualified
彼の家は資格がある
The size of the farmhouse does not exceed
農家の規模が以下を超えないこと
One-tenth of that 750 ping
750 ping の 10 分の 1
but the lane next to him
でも彼の隣の車線は
Plus those street trees planted
それに街路樹が植えられている
usually illegal
通常は違法
So if the Council of Agriculture or the county government
したがって、農業評議会または郡政府が
Strictly enforce
厳重に執行する
you go to practice every month
あなたは毎月練習に行きます
Remove his illegal things immediately
彼の違法なものをすぐに撤去してください
he must be living very uncomfortable
彼はとても不自由な生活をしているに違いない
His villa is only a villa
彼の別荘は単なる別荘です
his way is gone
彼の道は消えた
His potted plant is gone too
彼の鉢植えもなくなってしまった
His magnetic paper is gone
彼の磁気紙はなくなってしまった
you make him very uncomfortable
あなたは彼をとても不快にさせます
Just you execute this
これを実行するだけです
You can accept it as a farmhouse test
農家のテストとして受け入れることができます
Then it depends on our county mayor
それは私たちの郡長次第です
Is there an exception to this
これに例外はありますか
In fact, there should be a so-called long-term plan
実際には、いわゆる長期計画があるはずです
long-term planning first
まずは長期的な計画を立てる
you want to go back to that mother law
あなたはその母なる法律に戻りたいのですか
You want to amend the Agricultural Development Regulations
農業開発条例を改正したい
You need to draw paper, current agricultural construction methods
紙を描く必要がある、現在の農業工法
because in every country in the world
なぜなら世界中のどの国でも
I think there is a so-called
いわゆるあると思います
how to say strategic thinking
戦略的思考を何と言うか
Let's say I want to feed my billion people
たとえば、10億人に食事を与えたいとします。
How much good farmland should I have at least
少なくともどれくらいの良好な農地が必要ですか
I can feed these people
私はこの人たちに食事を与えることができる
Then I divide the farmland
それから農地を分割します
I said I will never allow you to buy or sell these farmlands
この農地の売買は絶対に許さないと言いました
No, you are not allowed to develop it for industrial use
いいえ、産業用に開発することは許可されていません
or other uses
または他の用途
You have to have this kind of strategic thinking
このような戦略的思考を持たなければなりません
Then you must go back to our strictest one
その場合は、最も厳格な方法に戻る必要があります。
go inside the law
法律の内側に入る
Mainland China, don't watch it blossom randomly
中国本土よ、無作為に開花するのを見てはいけません
it has some farmland you can never touch
決して触れてはいけない農地がある
it is strategic farmland thinking
それは戦略的農地思考です
it knows it has to feed a billion people
10億人を養わなければならないことを知っている
it must always have enough farmland
常に十分な農地がなければなりません
So it doesn't mess with
だから混乱しないよ
Although it is relatively marginal
比較的ギリギリではありますが、
that some farmland will be used
農地の一部が使用されることになる
but it has a bottom line
しかし、それには結論があります
We in Taiwan seem to have no bottom line
私たち台湾には利益がないようだ
If you arrive in Yilan, you will be very sad
宜蘭に着いたらとても悲しいことになるでしょう
I just passed through Yilan for our self-speaking event last week
先週のセルフスピーキングイベントのために宜蘭を通過したところです
You will find that half of Yilan's farmland has been removed
宜蘭の農地の半分が撤去されていることがわかります。
There is a villa in the middle of most of the farmland
ほとんどの農地の真ん中に別荘があります
And then there's our rooting policy
そして、私たちの応援ポリシーがあります
In fact, the benefits of the root cultivation policy were good at the beginning.
実際、根栽培政策の効果は当初は良好でした。
you prune and turn
あなたは剪定して向きを変えます
This solves two problems at the same time
これにより 2 つの問題が同時に解決されます
Our rural labor is not enough
私たちの田舎の労働力は十分ではありません
If the government has enough
政府に十分な資金があれば
You take that subsidy for root pruning money
根の剪定の補助金を受け取ります
half for farmers half for farmers
半分は農家のために 半分は農家のために
Give these young people who want to go to the countryside let him come to Monong
田舎に行きたい若者たちに、モノンに来させてください。
I think you can solve this rural labor problem
あなたならこの田舎の労働問題を解決できると思います
So if you make good use of the subsidy, it doesn't necessarily mean that it is completely wasted.
ですので、補助金を上手に活用すれば全くの無駄になるわけではありません。
But if you just go and let him prune there
でも、もしあなたが行って彼にそこで剪定をさせたら
Then your money is really a complete waste
それならあなたのお金は本当に無駄です
And this old farmer should have done it long ago
そしてこの年老いた農場主はずっと前にそれをやるべきだった
into our national pension system
国民年金制度に加入する
You can't possibly have a provisional regulation that hasn't been changed in 31 years
31年間変更されていない暫定規制などあり得ない
I think this is something our government should think about
これは私たちの政府が考えるべきことだと思います
The Basic Law of Agriculture is actually to combine all these
実は農業基本法というのは、これらすべてを組み合わせたものなのです。
The bill I discussed turned it into a full statute
私が議論した法案はそれを完全な法律に変えた
That's where our country's agriculture is headed
それが我が国の農業が向かうところです
this i think
これは私が思う
Because I have probably mentioned that it is the employment opportunity for agricultural talents in our country
なぜなら、それが我が国における農業人材の雇用の機会であるとおそらく述べたからです。
Then the next step is actually the policy issue we are facing in Taiwan now.
そして次のステップは、実は現在台湾で直面している政策課題なのです。
You only need one or two exceptions to the head of government agency and exception to the mayor of the county
政府機関の長に対する例外と郡長に対する例外は 1 つか 2 つだけ必要です
Probably there will be many problems, and it should be possible to decide
おそらく問題はたくさんあるだろうし、決断できるはずだ
But what we are really facing is this problem
しかし、私たちが実際に直面しているのはこの問題です
Our food independence in Taiwan is for food security
台湾における食料自給自足は食料安全保障のためです
You often hear about food security, but in fact it has a
食料安全保障についてよく聞きますが、実際には、
Let's say the UN's FAO in 1996
1996年の国連FAOとしましょう。
It has formulated a definition of what is called food security
いわゆる食料安全保障の定義を策定しました。
It simply means that when all people at all times have access to
それは単に、すべての人がいつでもアクセスできることを意味します。
and controlling sufficient quantities of high-quality food for an active and healthy life
活動的で健康的な生活のために十分な量の高品質の食品を管理すること
So now it's a matter of value and quantity
さて、問題は価値と量です
Enough and hopefully the entire population of the world
十分、できれば世界の全人口
But now we are facing many challenges
しかし今、私たちは多くの課題に直面しています
The increase in population is also due to the need for quality
人口の増加は質の必要性によるものでもあります
There is also an increase in agricultural production and a decrease in agricultural production.
農業生産の増加もあれば、農業生産の減少もあります。
The problem that the global environment becomes
地球環境が大きくなる問題
That means we have to produce enough food
つまり、十分な食料を生産しなければならないということです
to feed the global population is a big challenge
世界人口を養うことは大きな課題です
Why, in fact, you look at food security
実際、なぜ食料安全保障に注目するのか
The most important thing is to look at the bones
最も重要なことは骨を観察することです
Because bones are not just rice for eating
骨はただ食べるためのご飯ではないから
used as fodder
飼料として使用される
So bone is almost the vast majority of
したがって、骨はほぼ大部分を占めます。
source of calorie
カロリー源
So you have to see if the food supply is enough
だから食料供給が十分かどうかを確認する必要がある
Just look at the global bone production
世界の骨生産量を見てみよう
This blue one is from the past few decades
この青いのは過去数十年のものです
The one with global bone production
世界的な骨生産量を持つもの
increasing trend
増加傾向
That's actually a very
それは実際には非常に
re-markable achievement
顕著な功績
because you can see
見えるから
it's straight up
それはまっすぐです
from the green revolution
緑の革命から
After the Green Revolution of 1960
1960 年の緑の革命後
Always
いつも
keep going
立ち止まるな
that
それか
Straight up
まっすぐに
if that means
それが意味するなら
We scientists are so good
私たち科学者はとても優秀です
can make this
これを作ることができます
The food production line
食品製造ライン
keep this
持っていて
this
これ
is equivalent to a linear increase.
は線形増加に相当します。
we will face
私たちは直面します
In 2050 we will face
2050 年に私たちは直面するでしょう
food crisis
食糧危機
because this is
なぜならこれは
demand
要求
this is your surprise
これはあなたの驚きです
you can see until 2050
2050年まで見える
This gap will be much
このギャップは大きくなるだろう
that is
あれは
if we don't solve this problem
この問題を解決しないと
in 2050 there will be
2050年には
food
食べ物
worldwide
世界的に
food shortage problem
食糧不足問題
Once the problem of global food shortage
かつて世界的な食糧不足が問題になった
there will be war
戦争が起こるだろう
there will be a bend
曲がりがあるでしょう
so this is a
これは
very important question
非常に重要な質問
What about us in Taiwan?
台湾ではどうですか？
food security, let's look at food independence
食料安全保障、食料の自立について考えてみましょう
Everyone, if you look at the big countries in the world
皆さん、世界の大国を見てみると
Its agriculture must be ranked among the top in the world
その農業は世界のトップにランクされるに違いない
Except for Japan
日本を除く
Everyone, take a look at Huaguo's food independence
皆さん、華国の食の自立を見てください。
300%
３００％
so it is an agricultural exporting country
農産物輸出国ですからね
US 120%
米国 120%
Mainland China 70%
中国本土 70%
Taiwan 32%
台湾 32%
So that means we need
つまり、必要があるということです
70% of calorie is imported
カロリーの70％は輸入品
Then maybe you think you can buy it
それなら買ってもいいかもね
not so easy
そう簡単ではない
Everyone knows
みんな知ってる
In addition to rice, these stocks in Taiwan
米のほかに台湾にあるこれらの株は、
we can be autonomous
私たちは自律的になれる
corn for feed
飼料用のトウモロコシ
barley, wheat
大麦、小麦
Rely almost entirely on imports
ほぼ完全に輸入に頼っている
Then you may think that money is enough to buy
そうすると、お金で買えると思うかもしれません。
food is not that expensive
食べ物はそれほど高価ではありません
In 205 there was a look a few years ago
205では数年前に見られました
15 years ago there was a national
15年前には国立がありました
not the whole country
国全体ではない
There are several large granaries in the world
世界には大きな穀倉地帯がいくつかある
because of the drought
干ばつのせいで
Mainland China India Russia
中国本土 インド ロシア
their country is in drought
彼らの国は干ばつに陥っている
US pulls corn for reproductive alcohol
米国、生殖用アルコール目的でトウモロコシを摘出
So that year there were several places in the world
その年、世界にはいくつかの場所がありました
Its currency book is 4%
その通貨帳簿は4%です
4% is 50%
4%は50%です
Because the corn sold in the United States
アメリカで売られているトウモロコシだから
closely related to everyone
みんなと密接な関係がある
Most of the meat you eat is American
あなたが食べる肉のほとんどはアメリカ産です
grew up eating american corn
アメリカンコーンを食べて育った
pig sheep chicken
豚羊鶏
So that year Taiwan
それでその年、台湾は
Almost put our so-called war food stockpile
いわゆる戦争食糧備蓄がほぼなくなってしまう
Every year our Taiwan government
毎年、私たちの台湾政府は
will buy some rice
お米を買います
then save
それから保存します
after a few years
数年後
Then remove the older rice
次に古いお米を取り除きます
And then when we need
そして必要なときに
The government can provide emergency
政府は緊急事態を提供できる
We almost put that
ほぼそれを入れます
Our storage is all gone
ストレージがすべてなくなってしまいました
Inflation in Taiwan did not exceed 10% in that year
同年の台湾のインフレ率は10％を超えなかった
Otherwise we will have a crisis that year
そうしないとその年に危機が起きるだろう
that so
まあまあ
This shows Taiwan's food insecurity
これは台湾の食糧不安を示している
That
それか
Rice everyone look
ご飯みんな見て
We are 100% self-sufficient
私たちは100%自給自足しています
Then we need to import 6% because the WTO stipulates that we must import
WTO は輸入しなければならないと規定しているため、6% を輸入する必要があります。
but
しかし
Now Taiwan is also starting to face problems
今、台湾も問題に直面し始めている
It's just that I almost mentioned the farmland before.
ただ、先ほど農地のことをほとんど申し上げました。
We lost a lot of farmland
私たちは多くの農地を失いました
rural manpower
田舎の人材
and water resources
そして水資源
this is all
これですべてです
the problem we are facing
私たちが直面している問題
but in fact
しかし実際には
more serious
もっと深刻な
Even God is looking for trouble
神様もトラブルを探している
everybody
みんな
It's like global warming
地球温暖化みたいなもんだよ
I don't know if it will have a direct impact on Taiwan.
台湾に直接的な影響があるかどうかは分からない。
Because summer doesn't seem to be hotter than before
夏も以前ほど暑くないようなので
Although we complain sometimes it's hot
時々暑いと文句を言いますが
But climate and environmental changes caused by global warming
しかし、地球温暖化による気候や環境の変化
Some have particularly strong influence on Taiwan
台湾に特に強い影響力を持つ人もいる
Average daytime temperature in Taiwan over the past 100 years
過去100年間の台湾の日中の平均気温
only increase a little
少しだけ増える
will not exceed the level of world increase
世界の増加水準を超えることはない
But our night temperature is the average temperature at night
でも、私たちの夜の気温は夜の平均気温です
just increase it twice
2倍にするだけです
Don't underestimate these two times
この2回を過小評価しないでください
The global average pool is only 0.7 degrees
世界の平均気温はわずか0.7度
Taiwan facility twice
台湾施設2回
There is the International Rice Organization and they have scientists doing experiments
国際米機関があり、科学者が実験を行っています
If your temperature increases by one degree at night
夜に体温が1度上がったら
Your rice yield will be super white
あなたの米の収穫量は超白になります
Because usually the role of daytime light
普段は昼間の光の役割をしているので、
night
夜
colder weather
寒い天気
That means that the metabolism of plants will Slowdown
つまり植物の新陳代謝が鈍化するということです
will be slower
遅くなります
So it consumes less energy
そのためエネルギー消費が少なくて済みます
So it is equivalent to removing its energy at night
つまり、夜間にエネルギーを除去することに相当します。
Then if your temperature is higher at night
夜間に体温が高くなる場合
Your metabolic rate will be higher
代謝率が高くなります
So your output will be lower then
したがって、出力は低くなります
this is the theory
これが理論です
But that is to say, it should be considered as full REASM
しかし、つまり、完全な REASM として考慮される必要があります。
The climate change caused by global warming
地球温暖化による気候変動
It's not just the high temperature I'm talking about
私が言っているのは高温だけではありません
Sometimes Draught
時々ドラフト
flooded
浸水した
and extreme climate
そして異常気象
That's all scientific proof
それはすべて科学的証拠です
That is to say, there are many reports
つまり、報告が多いのです
The so-called extreme climate is
いわゆる異常気象とは、
You may feel that
そう感じるかもしれません
Although it is our average temperature
私たちの平均気温ですが
The temperature remains almost the same during the day
日中もほぼ同じ気温が続きます
but you can feel
でもあなたは感じることができます
can it feel like
って感じでしょうか？
sometimes very cold days
時々とても寒い日があります
a few more days
あと数日
And sometimes it's very cold
そして時々とても寒いです
Especially hot days will pop up suddenly like this
特に暑い日はこうやって突然現れるのですね
when it shouldn't be hot
暑くないはずのときに
it will pop up
それはポップアップします
So this is all documented
これはすべて文書化されています
So although it is
だから、そうだとしても
That is to say, it doesn't look particularly serious.
つまり、特に深刻な状況ではないようです。
But this is for agricultural aid countries
でもこれは農業援助国向けの話
This effect is particularly large
この効果は特に大きい
the problem is
問題は
well if we admit
まあ、私たちが認めるなら
That is to say, now there is global warming and climate change
つまり、今、地球温暖化と気候変動が起こっているのです。
That's an upside-down for us in Taiwan
それは台湾の我々にとってはひっくり返った事だ
Does it actually affect
実際に影響はありますか
that this
これは
i don't have an answer right now
今は答えがありません
But let's start by asking the question
しかし、まずは質問から始めましょう
Does it directly affect
直接的に影響するのか
that climate change
その気候変動
that is to say especially that
それは特にそれを言います
temperature change
温度変化
resulting in two most important
その結果、最も重要な 2 つの結果が得られます
The most important influence on inversions is
インバージョンに最も重要な影響を与えるのは、
Disease species and its accelerated evolution
病気の種とその加速した進化
I'll give you this example later
この例については後ほど説明します
Then it also affects
そうするとそれも影響する
Your output and real volume
出力と実際の音量
This is an experiment conducted by academician Liu Shaocheng of our middle school
これは私たちの中学校の学者、劉少成が行った実験です
Then Barton 9 is Taiwan, as I mentioned earlier.
それからバートン9は先ほども言いましたが台湾です。
is our average daily temperature over the past few decades
過去数十年間の毎日の平均気温です
it doesn't change much
あまり変わりません
But its temperature difference between the sun and the moon decreases and the temperature annoyance increases
しかし、太陽と月の温度差は減少し、温度への不快感は増加します。
This is Academician Liu Shaocheng's Publication
これは学者、劉少成氏の出版物です。
If you have high temperature, what will be the impact on Taiwan's production
高温になった場合、台湾の生産に影響はありますか?
The first one, if you come in high temperature
1つ目は、高温になった場合
It happens to be in the flowering period when the pattern is forming or the period when it is about to bear fruit
たまたま模様が形成されつつある開花期か、結実しようとしている時期です。
It will not be affected when the temperature is about 33 degrees
気温が33度程度であれば影響を受けません。
As far as Pollination is concerned, the output will be low
受粉に関する限り、生産量は低くなります
As I said earlier, if you increase the temperature rejection, the production will decrease by 10%.
先ほども言いましたが、温度阻止率を上げると生産量は 10% 減少します。
encouraged from
から励まされた
That is, you take that, that is to say, you collect the gold
つまり、あなたはそれを取る、つまりゴールドを集めます
and then, right there
そして、すぐそこに
Endo Spen is when refilling is encouraged
エンドスペンは補充が推奨されるときです
If the temperature is very high, there will be fishy white
温度が非常に高いと白っぽくなります
I'll show you one of those later
後ほどお見せします
A photo, then this kind of white rice with fishy mist is the empty egg
写真を撮ったら、生臭い霧がかかったこの種のご飯は空の卵です
eat no nutrition
栄養を食べない
Then this is me from National Taiwan University
それでは、こちらは国立台湾大学の私です
At that time, the agronomy department was the play director, Lu Hushen
当時、農学部門は演劇監督の陸虎深でした。
Now is the era borrowed by the director of the Science and Technology Department of the Agricultural Committee
今は農業委員会科学技術部長のお借りした時代です
Well, we in Taiwan actually have something to do with the planting of waterways.
そうですね、私たち台湾は実は水路の植栽に関わっています。
Very good management, so every year the government announces
非常に優れた経営を行っているため、毎年政府が発表しています。
Declare, review first, that is, you will
まず宣言し、レビューします。つまり、
How many farmers have to plant how much, how much
何人の農家がどれだけの量を植えなければならないか
the waterway of the work, and then he will estimate that is to say
仕事の水路、そしてそれから彼はそれを見積もるだろう、つまり
What is the total output of this strain you are planting now?
あなたが今植えているこの株の総生産量はいくらですか?
So at the beginning of every year he
それで毎年初めに彼は
He would say that I estimate that Taiwan will
彼は、私たちの台湾はそうなると予想している、と言うだろう。
How much is rice production
米の生産量はどれくらいですか
Then one year later there are actual numbers
そして1年後には実際の数字が出る
Usually the Internet was established 20 or 30 years ago
通常、インターネットは 20 ～ 30 年前に確立されました。
Our government is very powerful
私たちの政府は非常に強力です
The predictions are very accurate
予測は非常に正確です
That is, your total output
つまり、あなたの総生産量
The estimated output is about the same as your actual output
推定出力は実際の出力とほぼ同じです
Then this is for our management
それでは、これは私たちの管理用です
our economy
私たちの経済
It's very important whether you want to buy rice or not
お米を買いたいかどうかはとても重要です
But look at the past few years
しかしここ数年を見てみると
This is the data Mr. Lu Wusen has
これはLu Wusen氏が持っているデータです
In the past few years he has been on mission
ここ数年、彼は任務に就いていた
almost ten percent
ほぼ10パーセント
Does it sound like what I said earlier?
先ほど言ったことのように聞こえますか？
Because it means that the warming temperature of the previous autumn
前年秋の気温の上昇を意味するため、
It seems that there will be a direct correlation
直接的な相関関係がありそうな気がする
Well of course it's not evidence
まあもちろん証拠にはならないけど
but we're going to ask
しかし、私たちは尋ねるつもりです
Is this the reason?
これが理由ですか？
Why our output is higher than our estimate
なぜ生産量が予測よりも高くなるのか
so much less
はるかに少ない
ten percent less
10パーセント少ない
that's a lot
それは多いです
that's what i said
それは私が言ったことです
Encourage the enrichment period If your temperature is greater than 33 degrees
体温が 33 度を超える場合は、栄養強化期間を奨励してください。
You will see this opaque
これが不透明であることがわかります
this opaque this
この不透明なこれ
we call this
私たちはこれをそう呼んでいます
negative new white
ネガティブニューホワイト
Then this empty egg has no nutritional value.
そうすると、この空の卵には栄養価がありません。
because it encourages enrichment
それは豊かさを促すからです
That nutrient has not been deposited
その栄養素が蓄積されていない
So in Taiwan, you buy rice with that grade.
台湾ではその等級のお米を買います。
if you see
見たら
a lot of this
これをたくさん
that
それか
looks like
のように見える
pure white opaque
純白不透明
don't buy that
それは買わないでください
that is the cheapest
それが一番安いです
that so
まあまあ
that is
あれは
if you
もし、あんたが
pre-autumn warming
秋前の温暖化
will have the effect of these
これらの効果があるでしょう
the most important
最も重要な
seriously ill
重病
accelerated evolution
加速した進化
so
それで
even if it is silent
たとえ黙っていても
professor his age
教授の年齢
He just suggested
彼はちょうど提案した
we are technically
私たちは技術的には
what to develop
何を開発するか
The first is to have
1つ目は、
Breeding of softening two-fat rice
軟化二太米の育種
shadow technology
シャドウテクノロジー
water mixed and oxygen mixed
水と酸素を混ぜたもの
Regulated Cultivation Techniques
規制された栽培技術
Surveillance and Outbreak System Recommendations
監視およびアウトブレイク システムの推奨事項
This is more traditional
こちらの方が伝統的ですね
the field of agriculture
農業の分野
So Chinese medicine hospital probably
じゃあ漢方病院かな
research in this area
この分野の研究
but this
しかしこれは
With some of our Chinese medicine hospital
漢方病院の一部と
teacher of plants
植物の先生
there is some correlation
ある程度の相関関係はあります
Because our hospital
なぜなら当院は
There are many teachers who make plants
植物を作る先生もたくさんいます
The study of interaction with the environment
環境との相互作用の研究
that so
まあまあ
so
それで
I am here
私はここにいます
Probably about five years ago
たぶん5年くらい前かな
we formed a team
私たちはチームを結成しました
just want it
ただ欲しいだけ
Actually the most
実は一番多いのは
to build
構築する
a platform
プラットフォーム
that is
あれは
We consider that we are Taiwan
私たちは自分たちが台湾であると考えています
how to quote this
これをどう引用するか
Global Warning affects us everywhere
地球規模の警告はあらゆる場所で私たちに影響を与えます
Then its idea is that you want
その場合、そのアイデアは、あなたが望むということです
Actually we're not the only ones thinking this way
実はこのように考えているのは私たちだけではありません
In fact, the world told me
実際、世界は私にこう言いました
Now there needs to be a
今必要なのは、
Second Green Revolution
第二次緑の革命
and you
あなたも
The first green revolution was when you just
最初の緑の革命は、あなたがちょうど
that is
あれは
with a lot of feedback
たくさんのフィードバックとともに
Plenty of that sasom season
サソムの季節がたっぷり
Then you just have enough output
そうすれば、十分な出力が得られます
that's good
それは良い
But the new generation
しかし、新しい世代は
The Second Green Revolution
第二次緑の革命
Because our problems are different
私たちの問題は違うから
Because the environment you face is not like before
あなたが直面する環境は以前とは違うからです
Because you only need to overflow a seed before
シードをオーバーフローするだけで済みますので、
because of your climate change
気候が変わるから
not so suddenly
そんなに突然ではない
So our idea is to say
そこで私たちの考えはこう言います
we want to build a platform
私たちはプラットフォームを構築したいと考えています
It is equal to having a Swar Team
Swarチームを持つことと同じです
called the Rapid Strike Force
ラピッドストライクフォースと呼ばれる
That cooperates with, for example, the person who makes the ring change
それは、例えば指輪を変える人などと協力します。
They probably can predict
彼らはおそらく予測できるだろう
In other words, how will the environment change in the next few years?
言い換えれば、今後数年間で環境はどのように変化するでしょうか？
For example, Taiwan said that there will be drought in the future
例えば、台湾は将来干ばつが起こるだろうと言いました。
there will be a drought
干ばつが起こるだろう
Or say there will be too many fish
あるいは魚が多すぎると言うか
Or in spring when it shouldn't be hot
あるいは、暑くないはずの春に
it will be too hot
暑すぎるでしょう
then we hope we have that ability
それなら私たちもその能力を持っていることを願っています
It's from our tour kids
ツアーの子供たちからです
inside the toolbox
工具箱の中
reserve one
1つ予約してください
Can cope with the next three or four years
今後3～4年は耐えられる
The crops of the new environment
新しい環境の作物
That's because rice is the most important
お米が一番大事だから
So we use rice as our platform
そこで私たちは米をプラットフォームとして使用します
just want to build a platform
ただプラットフォームを構築したいだけです
equal to rapid strike force
急速な打撃力に等しい
That is, we need to be able to quickly preseed
つまり、迅速にプレシードできる必要があります。
you if we can predict the environment
環境を予測できたら
What kind of environment do we need our rice to face
お米にはどんな環境が必要なのか
then we will pre-release this new platform
その後、この新しいプラットフォームをプレリリースします
to grow in this environment
この環境で成長するために
This is our idea
これが私たちの考えです
So what we're looking for should probably be
したがって、私たちが探しているものはおそらく次のとおりであるはずです
In our country, that is to say
それは私たちの国です
Make plants interact with the environment
植物を環境と相互作用させる
quite accomplished
かなり完成度が高い
mostly from
ほとんどから
Academia Sinica
中央研究院
Agro-life Center Zhiwei Institute
農生中心 植威所
There is also a marriage office
結婚相談所もあります
Then we also found the National Taiwan University Department of Agronomy
そして、国立台湾大学農学部も見つけました。
and Central Agronomy Department
中央農学部
And some teachers from the farm
そして農場の先生たちも
We are mainly divided into three teams
大きく3つのチームに分かれています
The first is to resist disease
まずは病気に抵抗することです
The second is heat resistant
2つ目は耐熱性です
The third is to raise questions and use
3 つ目は、質問を提起し、使用することです。
This is actually
これは実際には
You want to develop permaculture
パーマカルチャーを発展させたい
will face this problem
この問題に直面するだろう
So in total we have
つまり、合計すると、
seven sub-plans
7つのサブプラン
the first is
一つ目は
The first team and the second team
第一チームと第二チーム
It's me and Mr. Wang Qiangsheng
私と王強生さんです
It is the Department of Agronomy of Central University
中央大学農学部です
And Teacher Lin Dajun
そしてリン・ダジュン先生
farm office
農事所的
Let's
しましょう
to study Taiwan's waterways
台湾の水路を研究する
Osteobacterium albicans, pathogenic mechanism, and wedding papers
オステオバクテリウム・アルビカンス、発症メカニズム、および結婚報告書
I will talk about the details of the comparison experiment later.
比較実験の詳細については後述します。
Then the team used by Lu Husheng and Changyi is anti-heat
そして、Lu HushengとChangyiが使用するチームはアンチヒートです
Then this, these four are the absorption of plant breeding
それからこれ、この４つが植物育種の吸収です。
The wedding paper mechanism used
ウェディングペーパーの仕組みを採用
That's actually very important
それは実はとても重要なことなのです
Because plants are the basic elements to maintain plant growth
植物は植物の成長を維持するための基本的な要素であるため、
Including sunlight, water, air and minerals
太陽の光、水、空気、鉱物など
Water and sunlight, of course, sunlight is free
水と太陽、太陽にはもちろんお金はかかりません
but water water resources
しかし水 水資源
So we hope that the waterway we pre-existed
したがって、私たちが以前から存在していた水路があったことを願っています
In the future, you may not need to use so many neutrons
将来的には、それほど多くの中性子を使用する必要がなくなるかもしれません
especially mineral elements
特にミネラル要素
Like the egg spirit armor is the three most important we call marcoelement
卵の精霊の鎧がマルコエレメントと呼ばれる最も重要な3つであるように、
That is, plants need a lot of nutrients to grow well
つまり、植物が元気に育つにはたくさんの栄養が必要なのです
some of that is tiny
その一部は小さいです
So several of our teachers have made eggs zero
それで私たちの何人かの先生が卵をゼロにしました
There are also iron cores and copper ones
鉄芯や銅芯もあります
Then you may think
それからあなたはこう思うかもしれません
what's so great about your elements
あなたの要素の何がそんなに素晴らしいのか
Seems like zeros are everywhere
どこにでもゼロがあるように見える
But in fact, zero is the most serious problem currently facing
しかし実際には、ゼロは現在直面している最も深刻な問題です
Because most of the zeros on Earth can't actually be absorbed by plants
なぜなら、地球上のゼロのほとんどは実際には植物によって吸収されないからです。
Only a part of the limited amount can
数量限定の一部のみとさせていただきます
We call it bioavailability, which is what plants can use
私たちはそれをバイオアベイラビリティと呼んでおり、植物が利用できるものです
Then these zeros are only available in a few countries
これらのゼロはいくつかの国でのみ利用可能です
So you want the current zero return
したがって、現在のゼロリターンが必要です
That has already started means that it should be used up in a few decades
すでに始まっているということは、数十年後には使い果たされるはずだ
So the plants you're going to grow now are
さて、これから育てようとしている植物は、
You need to be able to use fewer zeros
使用できるゼロの数を減らす必要がある
But still look good
しかし、それでも見た目は良い
Well, this is actually a big trick
いや、実はこれが大きなトリックなんです
easy to say
言うのはたやすい
but not so easy
しかし、それほど簡単ではありません
so
それで
Of course the egg is also very important
もちろん卵も大切です
But because suddenly there are fine grains in it that can solidify the egg
しかし、突然、卵を固める可能性のある細かい粒子が入っているため、
So it should be relatively less deductible
したがって、控除額は比較的少なくなるはずです
But this and these three
でもこれとこの３つ
That's what our comprehensive Nutrient team is doing
それが当社の包括的な栄養チームが取り組んでいることです
So we are the most plant-based nutrition team
つまり、私たちは最も植物ベースの栄養チームです
Their most important thing is to improve the nutritional value of food
最も重要なことは食品の栄養価を向上させることです
and improve crop quality
作物の品質を向上させる
And reduce the nutrition of sweet food
そして甘いものの栄養を減らす
that this
これは
if you can achieve this
これを達成できれば
you can help our environment
あなたは私たちの環境を助けることができます
call
電話
Because all the farmland now
だって今は全部農地だから
Whether in Taiwan or around the world
台湾でも世界中でも
are beginning to face the so-called prolongation problem
いわゆる長期化問題に直面し始めている。
because you use too much nutrition
栄養を使いすぎるから
Most of them are silent in the soil.
それらのほとんどは土の中で沈黙しています。
that of your soil
あなたの土壌のこと
If there are many of these Nutrient
これらの栄養素が多ければ
its continuation will
その継続は
relative increase
相対的な増加
so you lose too many times
だから何度も負ける
Your farmland will not be usable after a long time
時間が経つと農地が使えなくなる
So this can achieve several goals in one fell swoop
これにより、複数の目標を一度に達成できるようになります
The rest of the time I'll talk about my own experiments
残りの時間は私自身の実験について話します
Because Zhongyan always has to do experiments.
なぜなら、Zhongyan は常に実験をしなければならないからです。
I spoke a lot of formal questions today
今日はたくさんの正式な質問について話しました
It's not good if you don't talk about some of your own research results.
自分の研究結果について話さないのは良くありません。
so
それで
So right at the beginning of our project
プロジェクトの開始直後に
I was with Mr. Wang Qiangsheng from Chung Hsing University
私は中興大学の王強生さんと一緒でした。
we will team up
私たちはチームを組むよ
we decided to solve
私たちは解決することにしました
The so-called disease of Taiwan's waterways
いわゆる台湾の水路の病気
There are three major diseases in waterways
水道有三大病害
The first one is called white leaf mushroom disease
1つ目は白葉きのこ病と呼ばれるものです
It was caused by a Seo Joon
ソジュンが原因だった
The other one is called stealing fever
もう一つは盗む熱と呼ばれるものです
that was made by a
それはある人によって作られた
caused by a fungus
真菌によって引き起こされる
The other Wengu disease is also caused by fungi
他のウェング病も真菌によって引き起こされます
Both bacterial blight and rice fever can be killed by good chemical pesticides
細菌性疫病とイネ熱はどちらも優れた化学農薬で死滅させることができます
Everyone, have you seen the Mystery Fever?
みなさん、ミステリーフィーバーはご覧になりましたか？
Kun Bingbei once killed in a field and passed out
クン・ビンベイはかつて野原で殺され、気を失った
He just wants to pre-spray
彼はただ事前にスプレーしたいだけなのです
Because he just wants to kill pesticides and kill white leaf mushroom bacteria
なぜなら、彼は農薬を殺して白葉茸の細菌を殺したいだけだからです。
So what I mean by this is that he can kill but is very poisonous
つまり、これが言いたいのは、彼は人を殺すことができるが、非常に有毒であるということです
It's not good for the land, it's not good for people
土地にも良くない、人にも良くない
Usually this white leaf mushroom disease breaks out after typhoon
通常、この白い葉茸の病気は台風の後に発生します
Because after the typhoon, everyone will be injured
台風の後はみんな怪我するから
Once the leaves are injured, it is easier for bacteria to enter
葉が傷つくと雑菌が侵入しやすくなります
So you often see that fever break out for no reason
理由もなく発熱することがよくあります
Usually there are some natural disasters
通常、自然災害が発生します
this disease
この病気
In fact, rice is being made all over the world
実はお米は世界中で作られているんです
But we in Taiwan must do rice research by ourselves
しかし、私たち台湾人は自分たちでお米の研究をしなければなりません
there is a reason
理由があります
Because there are two main species of rice cultivated
栽培されているお米は主に2種類あるため、
North of the Yangtze River is called Japónica
長江の北はジャポニカと呼ばれます
It is the bee rai rice that you like to eat
あなたが食べたいのはビーライライスです
The south of the Yangtze River is called Indica
長江以南はインディカと呼ばれる
Your name is Zelami
あなたの名前はゼラミです
Taiwan is the only southern country
台湾は唯一の南の国です
bee rai rice
ビーライライス
種 Japanese
種 日本人
Because the Japanese introduced it to the Bamboo Lake in Yangmingshan and began to plant it.
それは、日本人が陽明山の竹湖に導入し、植え始めたからです。
Slowly let it loop down to level ground
ゆっくりと平らな地面までループダウンさせます
After decades of breeding
数十年の繁殖を経て
Our Taiwan is now the only one in the world
私たちの台湾は今や世界で唯一のものです
south country eat
南国で食べる
以Japanese
以日本語
When our main rice is our door
メインのお米が玄関口になるとき
There are pros and cons to this
これには賛否両論あります
Because at least I personally prefer to eat red rice
少なくとも個人的には赤飯を食べるのが好きなので
And it's not very tasty in Leme
そしてレメではあまり美味しくない
Because this is usually the pathogenic bacteria and its season family
これは通常、病原性細菌とその季節性ファミリーであるため、
There is that special relationship we call a bend-to-bend relationship
私たちがベンド・トゥ・ベンド関係と呼ぶ特別な関係があります。
That is to say, a certain physiological swelling
つまり、ある種の生理的なむくみ
Strains that usually have some waterways
通常、いくつかの水路がある株
It will fight against this physiological small swelling
この生理的な小さなむくみと闘います
it will have disease resistance genes
病気に強い遺伝子を持つだろう
So there is that correspondence
それでその通信があります
So it is very important for you to know what this physiological edema is
したがって、この生理的浮腫が何であるかを知ることは非常に重要です。
Then there is a unit under the United Nations in the Philippines called
それから、フィリピンには国連の下に、と呼ばれる部隊があります。
International Water Course Research Center
国際水コース研究センター
They specialize in Lemi our name is Indica
彼らはレミを専門としています。私たちの名前はインディカです
Then they have 21 standard strains
そうすると標準株が 21 個あります
each with a fungus resistant to white leaf mushroom
それぞれ白葉茸に耐性のある菌を持つ
Gene, that is to say, the waterway has that
ジーン、つまり水路にはそれがある
Then if you go to Asian countries to collect his white patriotic disease bacteria
それからアジア諸国に行って彼の白人愛国病菌を集めたら
You'll find 21 strains of white patriotism
21 種類の白人の愛国心が見つかります
Exactly almost 1 to 1
まさにほぼ1対1
That is to say, if you carry this disease-resistant bacteria
つまり、この病気に対する耐性菌を持っていると、
You can resist physiological swelling 1 to 1
生理的むくみには1対1で抵抗できます
That's irresistible to others
それは他の人にとっては抵抗できないものです
So this is an example
これは一例です
You can see us talking about this
私たちがこれについて話しているのがわかります
This one has this antibacterial
これには抗菌効果があります
Then you see he is not resistant to this white patriotic germ
そうすれば、彼はこの白人の愛国的な細菌に抵抗力がないことがわかります
He only fights one or two
彼は1人か2人しか戦わない
Then these two will be
そうするとこの二人はこうなります
That is to say, he has similar healing bacteria
つまり、彼は同様の治癒細菌を持っています
So you have this disease-resistant bacteria
つまり、この病気に耐性のある細菌がいるということです
you'll deal with this and this
あなたはこれとこれに対処します
but not resistant to other diseases
しかし他の病気には耐性がない
So you must know the physiological small swelling
だから生理的な小さなむくみを知っておく必要がある
Only then will you be able to predict the disease-resistant water to
そうして初めて、病気に強い水を予測できるようになります。
Then why does Taiwan have to do it by itself?
では、なぜ台湾が単独でやらなければならないのでしょうか？
Then I will give you the reason why Taiwan must do it by itself
では、台湾が単独でやらなければならない理由をお話します。
that's us
それが私たちです
Just say when I come back
戻ってきたら言ってください
That is
あれは
on behalf of the farm
農場を代表して
The existing Baiyugu bacteria in Taiwan
台湾に現存する白玉菌
Find the so-called wedding paper label
いわゆるウェディングペーパーラベルを見つける
help him
彼を助けて
It's like helping him create that ID card.
そのIDカードの作成を手伝うようなものです。
There are about five major species in Taiwan
台湾には主に5種類ほどの動物が生息しています
That's probably distributed in
おそらく配布されているものだと思います
distributed in these places
こんなところに配布されてる
Then this is our 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 like this
それから、これは私たちの 1、2、3、4、5 です。
You can watch
あなたは見ることができます
should be
あるべきです
this top
この上に
And here's the frequency he distributed
そしてこれが彼が配布した周波数です
That's really hard work
それは本当に大変な仕事だよ
because
なぜなら
Taiwan before almost 1990
1990 年近く以前の台湾
the collection of races
レースのコレクション
very complete
非常に完全な
we collect every year
私たちは毎年集めます
Our farming units are located all over the province
私たちの農業ユニットは州内全域にあります
collect back
回収する
Then come back and put it in that freezer
それから戻ってきて冷凍庫に入れてください
Then you'll study its physiological properties in the future
その後、将来その生理学的特性を研究することになります
you can take it out
取り出すことができます
But look at this picture
でもこの写真を見てください
Between 1990 and 2010
1990 年から 2010 年の間
it collects infrequently
まれに集まります
Especially in the past ten years, almost completely broken
特にここ10年はほぼ完全に壊れた
So we took out all the things hidden in the freezer by the farm
そこで私たちは農場のそばの冷凍庫に隠していたものをすべて取り出しました
Then compare it with what they collected back then
その後、当時収集したものと比較してください
As a result, in fact, Taiwan used to
その結果、実際、台湾はかつて
So there should be no new strains in the past 20 years
したがって、過去20年間に新しい株は存在しないはずです
Just these four
この4つだけ
One of them is called one and one be
そのうちの 1 つは one と呼ばれ、もう 1 つは be と呼ばれます
so it's still
だからまだだよ
That means you haven't had a new one in the past 20 years
つまり、過去20年間新しいものを持っていなかったということです
But if you do the independent trust test
しかし、独立した信頼テストを行うと、
Because we put these collected 20 years ago in the freezer
20年前に集めたものを冷凍庫に入れていたので
frozen firm take it out
凍ったまま取り出します
can activate it
それをアクティブにすることができます
and ask how poisonous it is
そしてそれがどれくらい有毒なのか尋ねます
Then put the newcomer
それから新人を入れます
This is the same species, the same biological race, so let's ask how poisonous it is
これは同じ種、同じ生物学的種族です、それでどれくらい有毒なのか聞いてみましょう
The answer is that Gang Xincai's toxicity is stronger than that of his relatives twenty years ago
答えは、姜新才の毒性は20年前の彼の親戚の毒性よりも強いということです
That is to say, as time changes, his toxicity will increase
つまり時間が経てば経つほど毒性が増すということだ
So he is not there obediently, his toxicity is getting stronger and stronger
だから彼は素直にそこにいない、彼の毒性はますます強くなる
That's what it means. If you want to predict your own in Taiwan, you must follow the evolution of the continuation.
台湾で自分自身を予測したい場合は、継続の進化を追跡する必要があります。
You need to pre-produce new varieties that can resist these white frontal bone disease bacteria over time
これらの白色前頭骨疾患細菌に長期にわたって抵抗できる新しい品種を事前に生産する必要があります。
Then why can't we rely on others
ではなぜ他人に頼ることができないのか
Then we have the so-called high-throughput sequencing
次に、いわゆるハイスループットシーケンスがあります。
So you can easily fix the exhausted early hardware
そのため、使い果たされた初期のハードウェアを簡単に修正できます
Then let's take Taiwan, both of which belong to Taiwan
それでは、台湾を取り上げましょう。どちらも台湾に属します。
This is the most toxic, this is not so strong
これが最も有毒ですが、これはそれほど強力ではありません
Then if I draw a line here, it means his chromosome series here
ここに線を引くと、それはここでの彼の染色体系列を意味します
a little different
少し違う
You can see this one in Taiwan is very similar
これは台湾のものとよく似ていることがわかります
no difference
変わりはない
give you a test
テストをしてください
Hui Libing is closer to Taiwan
ホイ・リービンは台湾に近い
Then we also decided to continue
それから私たちも継続することにしました
icy gray
アイシーグレー
Then Japanese and Korean bacteria
それから日本と韓国の細菌
Someone has already ordered
すでに注文した人がいます
let's compare it
比べてみましょう
You guys think it's relatively close
比較的近いと思いますよ
Huili Bing's Baiyan Mushroom Bing's Mushroom
ホイリ・ビンのバイヤンキノコ ビンのキノコ
It is more similar to the bacteria in Taiwan
台湾の細菌に似ています
Or Japanese and Korean
あるいは日本人と韓国人
You guys are amazing
あなたたちは素晴らしいです
Although Japan and South Korea are farther away than us
日本と韓国は遠く離れていますが
it is as it may be
それはあり得ることだ
Because you have already said
なぜならあなたはすでに言ったからです
The rice season group followed it with bacteria
ご飯の季節グループは細菌でそれに続きました
are co-evolved
共進化している
So it still has its characteristics
まだその特徴が残っているので、
but there is a short book
でも短い本があります
This is from Taiwan
これは台湾から来たものです
this is korean
これは韓国人です
this japanese
この日本人
It's icy gray
アイシーグレーです
If I have this kind of
こういうの持ってたら
like crossed lines
交差した線のように
just say
言うだけ
it has major changes
大きな変更があります
the location of that gene
その遺伝子の位置
In other words, genetically, it is actually a relatively large change.
つまり、遺伝的には、実は比較的大きな変化なのです。
Variability is relatively large
変動が比較的大きい
So the more you have this cross
だから、この十字架を持てば持つほど、
means it is more different
もっと違うという意味です
so you look at japan
だから日本を見てみろよ
Korea is different from us
韓国は私たちとは違います
mostly straight
ほとんど真っ直ぐ
But you see in the Philippines
でもフィリピンを見ればわかります
look
見て
but
しかし
if you look carefully
よく見ると
these crossed
これらは交差しました
In fact, the most important gene
実は最も重要な遺伝子は、
These genes are all genes that cause white face bone disease
これらの遺伝子はすべて白顔骨疾患を引き起こす遺伝子です
that is
あれは
Our Taiwan albino bone disease bacteria
私たちの台湾アルビノ骨病菌
Although similar to Japan
日本と似ていますが、
but it has evolved a unique set of disease-causing genes
しかし、それは病気の原因となる独特の遺伝子セットを進化させてきました
so you have its unique disease-causing gene
つまり、独自の病気の原因となる遺伝子を持っているということです
you need to be unique
あなたはユニークである必要があります
Rice resistant to this disease-causing gene
この病気の原因となる遺伝子に耐性のあるイネ
so
それで
Only Taiwan has this bacteria in the world
この菌は世界で台湾だけが保有している
so you have to do it yourself
だから自分でやる必要がある
what others do is useless
他人がやることは無駄だ
So why do we have to make our own rice
ではなぜお米を自分で作らなければならないのか
that's why
それが理由です
Will do it for us, what others do is useless
私たちのためにやってくれる、他人がやっても無駄だ
Everyone probably agrees that today is not my topic
今日は私の話題ではないということにはおそらく誰もが同意するでしょう
Maybe next time Wang Mu will invite me again
次回は王武がまた私を誘ってくれるかもしれない
Besides, genetically modified crops are very safe
また、遺伝子組み換え作物は非常に安全です
But you all have this
でも皆さんもこれ持ってますよ
there may be some problems
いくつか問題があるかもしれません
but there is another way
でも別の方法があります
You can actually pre-sum
実際に事前合計することができます
And soon, it's called pre-marriage papers
そしてすぐに、それは結婚前書類と呼ばれます
Professor Wang Qiangsheng at the Agricultural Institute
農業研究所の王強生教授
image library
画像ライブラリ
That is to use Tainong No. 67
それはTainong No.67を使用することです
Tai Nong No. 67 Everyone must know him
Tai Nong No. 67 誰もが彼を知っているはず
Because the basmati rice you eat
あなたが食べるバスマティライスだから
What is the number of Geng, what is the number of Kaohsiung?
庚の数は何ですか、高雄の数は何ですか?
All are from Tainong No. 67
すべて太農67号より
his descendants
彼の子孫
Because Tainong 67 has a large output
Tainong 67 は出力が大きいため
He resists many environmental adversities
彼は多くの環境逆境に抵抗します
he looks good
彼はいい顔してる
Then he is also resistant to these bacteria
そうすれば、彼はこれらの細菌にも耐性があります
some neutral resistance
ある程度中立的な
So he is the general manager of Taiwan
つまり彼は台湾の総支配人です
the most important one
最も重要なもの
So Professor Wang Qiangqiang used
そこで王強強教授はこう言った。
We created a set called mutation library
突然変異ライブラリと呼ばれるセットを作成しました
That mutant library is yours
そのミュータントライブラリはあなたのものです
inside his descendants
彼の子孫の中に
There will be many new features
たくさんの新機能が登場します
Then Mr. Wang started to plug
それから王氏はプラグを差し込み始めました
Then he stuffed some
それから彼はいくつか詰め込んだ
Look at this ability to heal
見てください、この治癒能力
then he takes this
それから彼はこれを受け取ります
I just told you about the XF89
XF89についてお話しました。
That's the most poisonous bacteria
それは最も有毒な細菌です
Then he goes to try these and that mutant library
それから彼はあれこれのミュータントライブラリを試しに行きます
he finds out
彼は見つけます
This is the earliest rice in Taiwan called Tainong No. 1
台湾最古のお米「太農一号」
Then this is Tainong No. 67
では、こちらはタイノン67号です
That's the size he's really sick
それは彼が本当に病気であるサイズです
Then you can see that Tainong-1 is almost immune to resistance
すると、Tainong-1 はほぼ免疫力があることがわかります。
Tainong No. 1 is almost irresistible
Tainong No. 1 はほとんど魅力的です
Tainong No. 67 still has a considerable degree of resistance
Tainong No. 67 はまだかなりの抵抗を持っています
But Teacher Wang found a few
しかし、王先生はいくつかのことを見つけました
It is the descendant of Tainong No. 67
タイノン67号の子孫です
Then the following is the data in front of him
次に、彼の目の前にあるデータは次のとおりです
You can see this is Tainong 1
これがTainong 1であることがわかります
Natai Nong No. 67
ナタイ・ノン No.67
And this is stuffed by Mr. Wang
そしてこれは王さんが剥製したものです
you can see most of his
彼のほとんどを見ることができます
This is how we measure his ability to heal
これが彼の治癒能力を測る方法です
Then you can see Mr. Wang's rice
そうすると王さんのご飯が見えてきます
The new strain is very good
新しい品種はとても良いです
Then I can introduce by the way
それならついでに紹介してもいいよ
You probably don't know us
あなたはおそらく私たちのことを知らないでしょう
the name of the crop field grown
その作物ドメインの名前
Everyone, if you hear Tainong
皆さん、タイノンを聞いたら
Whether it's ripe bananas or anything
熟れたバナナでも何でも
just call tainong
タイノンに電話してください
It's all from our farming area
それはすべて私たちの農業地域からのものです
Then if you hear Kaohsiung
それで高雄と聞こえたら
What is the number in Kaohsiung
高雄の数字は何ですか
That's from the Kaohsiung Improvement Factory.
高雄改良工場のものです。
Then each of our counties and cities has an improvement plant
そして、私たちの郡や市にはそれぞれ改善工場があります。
But only those under the Council of Agriculture
ただし、農業評議会の管轄下にあるものに限ります。
have a flagship research unit
主力の研究ユニットを持っている
Agricultural Laboratory
農業試験場
So everyone, as long as you hear Tainong
だから皆さん、タイノンの声が聞こえる限り
Probably they came out of the domain
おそらくドメインから出てきたのでしょう
Their contribution to Taiwan's agriculture
台湾の農業への貢献
It's very big, everyone can do it, almost all vegetables and fruits have Tainong
とても大きくて誰でもできます、ほとんどすべての野菜と果物に太農が入っています
Everyone can, you should not be able to imagine
誰もができる、あなたには想像できないはず
The Yuquan fragrant pear you like to eat is called Tainong No. 71
それで、あなたが食べるのが好きな玉泉の香りのよい梨は、太農71号と呼ばれます。
Probably in the year after next, there will be Tainong No. 77 in the next few years
おそらく再来年、数年以内に台農77号が出るでしょう。
Even more fragrant than Tainong No. 71, not very easy to grow
Tainong No. 71 よりもさらに香りが高く、栽培はそれほど簡単ではありません
Because if it is fragrant, it is easy to attract sparrows
香りがあるとスズメが集まりやすいので
So, once Mr. Wang finds this
それで、王さんがこれを見つけたら、
This Tainong No. 67 that can resist the white ear bone disease bacteria in Taiwan
台湾の白耳骨病菌に耐性のあるこの台農67号
That's because Tainong No. 67 is still not as delicious as Tainong No. 71
それは、太農67号はまだ太農71号ほど美味しくないからです。
So it's now going to be called a backcross
だからこれからはバッククロスと呼ばれるようになる
In the case of backcrossing, it probably means that you want to pass it back from generation to generation.
戻し交配の場合は、世代から世代へと受け継いでいきたいということでしょう。
Then Teacher Wang started in 2014, so you are now in 2015
王先生は 2014 年に始めたので、あなたは今 2015 年です。
That is to say, what you mean by crossing back is to say
つまり、クロスバックとはどういう意味ですか?
Rice, for example, has about 25,000 genes
たとえば、イネには約25,000の遺伝子がある
that only
それだけ
A small segment is the gene to resist leukemia
小さなセグメントは白血病に抵抗する遺伝子です
So if you teach Islam once, you will
ですから、イスラム教を一度教えれば、
For example, I like Tainong No. 71 now
たとえば、今は Tainong No.71 が好きです
But I need the small piece of disease-resistant gene of Tainong 67
でも、Tainong 67 の病気耐性遺伝子の小さな部分が必要です
As soon as I teach, I will select the part of the gene that is resistant to the disease
教えたらすぐに、病気に強い遺伝子の部分を選択します
That means I'll get about 75% once I crossbreed.
つまり、交配したら約75％が得られることになります。
It is probably possible to stay on Tainong No. 71
タイノン71号に泊まる可能性はあるかもしれない
Only 25% are Tainong No. 67
Tainong No. 67 はわずか 25%
But it's not real, isn't it fragrant rice?
でも本物じゃない、香り豊かなご飯じゃないですか。
so you continue to muslim
それであなたはイスラム教徒を続ける
After a generation, it will reach about 95%
一世代後には約95%に達します
That's almost like turning into a basmati rice
まるでバスマティライスになったかのようだ
You will be Muslim about five times later
あなたはあと5回くらいイスラム教徒になるでしょう
You will change from Tainong 67 to Tainong 71
Tainong 67 から Tainong 71 に乗り換えます。
So it has been certified by the Council of Agriculture, that is to say
つまり、農業評議会によって認定されています。
The Tainong No. 71 that Mr. Wang taught in Islam
王先生が教えたイスラム教のタイノン71番
and a new strain
そして新株
Available in about two years
約2年で入手可能
It's modified from a gray machine for anti-white frontal disease
対白前線病用の灰色の機体を改造したもの
Fragrant rice overflowing with wedding paper imperial seeds
ウェディングペーパーインペリアルシードが溢れる香り豊かなご飯
Then he is doing number 77 now
それで彼は今77番をやっている
So this is a
これは
Works on very TDS
非常に TDS 上で動作します
Because you can't spend money on this kind of paper
こんな紙にお金はかけられないから
and to
そしてへ
you see everyone
みんな見てるよ
Muslim once a year
イスラム教徒は年に一度
So it takes four to five years of hard work
だから4～5年の努力が必要だ
But here comes the fragrant rice
でも、香り豊かなご飯が登場します
And without pesticides
しかも無農薬で
but as i said before
しかし、前にも言ったように
you have this
あなたはこれを持っています
Bacteria
細菌
Bacteria will follow and evolve
バクテリアも後を追って進化する
Mr. Wang is now predicting this channel
王氏は現在このチャネルを予測しています
If you don't help this channel
このチャンネルを助けないと
Anti-bacteria
抗菌
maybe five years from now
おそらく今から5年後
you have to do it again
もう一度やらなければなりません
Filter again
再度フィルターをかける
so
それで
The other half is my home
残りの半分は私の家です
looking for
探している
to replace
交換する
Pesticides used by Kun Beibei
クン・ベイベイが使用した農薬
how do we find
どうやって見つけますか
now is
今は
In fact, in the soil
実は土の中に
There are also many microorganisms
微生物もたくさんいます
They compete with each other in Vitality
彼らはバイタリティで互いに競い合う
So he often stunned and produced some compounds to kill other Seo Joon
そのため、彼はしばしば気絶させたり、他のソジュンを殺すためにいくつかの化合物を生成したりしました
because he wants to compete he is in full circle
彼は競争したいから、フルサークルにいるんだ
So a lot of Tulang's vitamins have coma compounds
したがって、トゥランのビタミンの多くには昏睡成分が含まれています
Can be used as a biological machine
生物機械として使用可能
Because he exists in nature
自然界に存在するから
He can use it to kill other Seo Joon
彼はそれを使って他のソジュンを殺すことができる
So it was actually very difficult to find this kind of thing before.
したがって、以前はこのようなものを見つけるのは非常に困難でした。
Often in five or ten years you still can’t find out what you saw
5年後、10年後も、自分が何を見たのか分からないこともよくある
That's because the so-called genomics still has a lot of progress
それは、いわゆるゲノミクスにはまだ多くの進歩があるからです
I'm talking to you now about a postgraduate student working for less than two years
私は今、2年未満の大学院生の仕事について話しています。
then we will find
それから私たちは見つけます
It's not that hard to find this way.
この方法を見つけるのはそれほど難しくありません。
That's when you smeared white leaf mushroom germs all over
その時君は白い葉茸の菌を全身に塗りつけたんだ
inside this incubator
この保育器の中には
Then you dig a hole in the middle
そして真ん中に穴を掘ります
Then you take that Seo Joon you want to try
それなら試してみたいソジュンを連れて行ってください
Let's see if he has the ability to kill white leaf mushroom disease
彼に白葉茸病を殺す能力があるかどうか見てみましょう
the middle of the hole
穴の真ん中
If he can kill Baiyan Bone Disease
もし彼が白岩骨病を殺すことができたら
He'll melt the white bone disease bacteria
白骨病菌を溶かしてくれるだろう
He will come out in circles
彼はグルグル出てくるだろう
then this is
それならこれは
Circle it, everyone, look at this
丸をつけてください、皆さん、これを見てください
Because he took pictures, this is the circle
彼が写真を撮ったので、ここはサークルです
Then you if this bacteria
このバクテリアが
he doesn't have that ability
彼にはその能力がありません
Said that he himself cannot be degraded
彼自身は貶められることはできないと述べた
Can't kill white face bone disease
白顔骨疾患を殺すことはできない
So this is the German style of what we call quick people
これがいわゆる「機敏な人」のドイツ流です
Now the problem is
さて問題は
you are going to find
あなたは見つけるつもりです
what compound
何の化合物
Because you can't just say I'm an orderly
秩序ある者だとは言えないから
Then my student
それから私の生徒
designed a set
セットをデザインした
That is
あれは
first step
最初の一歩
just put this
これを置くだけ
this bacteria
この細菌
He has the drug that kills the white bone disease
彼は白骨病を治す薬を持っている
He gave his whole order
彼はすべての命令を出しました
This bacterium is
この細菌は、
A teacher from Tamkang University, Wang Shanli
淡江大学の王善麗先生
He got out of the muddy mud of the Danshui River
彼は淡水河の泥の中から抜け出した
stuffed out
詰め込まれた
he originally wanted
彼はもともと望んでいた
When he raised this bacteria
彼がこの細菌を育てたとき
It is to
それは
with shrimp shells
用蝦殼
When the only source of nutrients
唯一の栄養源の場合
He actually wanted to dissociate the lower shell.
彼は実際には下部シェルを分離したかったのです。
Experiment to decontaminate Oh Han Jin
オ・ハン・キム氏の除染実験
But hear it's a treasure
でもそれは宝物だって聞いて
Because after my students tried
なぜなら、私の生徒たちが試した後だからです。
I found out that he has a lot of genes
彼にはたくさんの遺伝子があることが分かりました
It seems that some secondary metabolites can be produced
二次代謝物が生成されるようです
It can be used for sterilization
滅菌にも使えます
So if you're looking for this compound early on,
したがって、この化合物を早い段階で探している場合は、
If you use the traditional method, it will be very painful
従来の方法だとかなり痛いです
Especially people in our lab like to make wedding paper creatures
特に私たちの研究室の人々はウェディングペーパーの生き物を作るのが好きです
don't like chemistry
化学が好きではありません
So you're going to the wedding to identify the structure.
それで、構造を特定するために結婚式に行くことになります。
That's a student in my lab
それは私の研究室の学生です
definitely won't do it
絶対にやらないだろう
but with genetics you can do
しかし、遺伝学を使えばできるのです
Because we now know the sequence
順番がわかったので
about 1000 genes
約1000個の遺伝子
Then we have a technology that puts
そして、私たちは次のような技術を持っています。
What we call a carrier can
私たちがキャリアと呼ぶものは、
It's your turn to insert it into the gene at will
それを遺伝子に自由に挿入するのはあなたの番です
Then if you insert it into the gene
それを遺伝子に挿入すると
Genes cannot make normal proteins
遺伝子は通常のタンパク質を作ることができない
It looks like this...
こんな感じですね…
If you insert the key gene
鍵となる遺伝子を挿入すると
For example, I can kill albino frontal bacterium now
たとえば、アルビノ前頭菌を殺すことができるようになりました。
Then you would generate this
次に、これを生成します
Then if you...
それなら...
this is you if that...
それならこれがあなたです...
If our gene is inserted into this gene called CLP
CLPと呼ばれるこの遺伝子に私たちの遺伝子が挿入されると
just look at it...
見てください...
Its ability to integrate is not enough
統合する能力が十分ではない
Then you insert these two genes
次に、これら 2 つの遺伝子を挿入します。
the one of it won't blend in at all
そのうちの1つはまったく溶け込まない
So this one gives us a...
それで、これは私たちに...
a clue
手掛かり
That is to say, the one that can kill the albino frontal bacterium...
つまり、アルビノ前線菌を殺せるもの…。
compound of
の化合物
maybe it has something to do with this
もしかしたらこれと関係があるかもしれない
That...
それか...
My student he is very good
私の生徒はとても優秀です
Because at that time we had just killed a man from the United States
なぜなら、その時私たちはちょうどアメリカから来た男性を殺したばかりだったからです。
UC San Diego Wedding School Back
カリフォルニア大学サンディエゴ ウェディング スクール戻る
it is a support instrument
それはサポート楽器です
video support
ビデオサポート
I think the technology of video support device is actually very simple
ビデオ支援装置の技術は実はとてもシンプルだと思います
It's you who put Seo Joon here
ソジュンをここに置いたのはあなたです
Then Seo Joon will secrete
そしたらソジュンが分泌するよ
Then you shoot the laser up
それからレーザーを発射します
That instrument is your laser
その機器はあなたのレーザーです
break down your compound into smaller molecules
化合物をより小さな分子に分解する
Then you can analyze its molecular weight
その後、その分子量を分析できます
then use various compounds
その後、さまざまな化合物を使用します
then you can figure it out
そうすればそれを理解できるよ
That is to say, it is inside the circle
つまり円の内側です
how many compounds
化合物は何個ありますか
What is the molecular weight of its compound
その化合物の分子量はどれくらいですか
Then you have this precise molecular weight
そうすれば、この正確な分子量が得られます
You can go back and find out what kind of nucleic acid it is
戻って、それがどのような種類の核酸であるかを調べることができます
Then I told you again
それからもう一度言いました
I have these mutants
私にはこれらのミュータントがいます
it doesn't make these compounds
これらの化合物は作られません
So you compare what we say
それであなたは私たちが言うことを比較します
WireTimes and these mutants
WireTimes とこれらの変異体
you'll know soon
あなたはすぐにわかります
What the hell is that nucleic acid?
その核酸とはいったい何なのでしょうか？
can kill bone disease
骨の病気を殺すことができる
That's because
それは、
In terms of time, I will jump over quickly
時間的にはすぐに飛び越えてしまいます
That is to say, my students are usually ordinary people
つまり、私の生徒はたいてい普通の人です
About ten years, I think, about ten years of your skills
約10年、あなたのスキルの約10年だと思います
probably can make what he's doing now
おそらく彼が今やっていることは実現できるだろう
Then he said less than two years
それから彼は2年以内だと言いました
He found this compound
彼はこの化合物を見つけました
It is the fungus next to the Danshui River I just mentioned.
先ほどの淡水河の隣のキノコです。
he can stun this compound
彼はこの化合物を気絶させることができる
he will spend silver light
彼は銀色の光を過ごすだろう
He can kill the white leaf mushroom ice fungus
彼は白い葉のキノコ氷菌を殺すことができます
it's a product of nature
それは自然の産物です
And he produced a lot
そして彼はたくさんのことを生み出した
so he now we have
それで彼は今私たちにいます
We have Teacher Wang Qiangsheng
王強生先生がいます
The anti-bacteria of the white leaf mushroom ice of Mr. Wang Qiangsheng
王強生氏の白葉キノコ氷の抗菌
plus our compound
プラス当社の化合物
So my student ran to the Beiguo Farm of Chung Hsing University
そこで私の学生は中興大学の北国農場へ走りました。
do field experiments
フィールド実験をする
The field test is to use Honglaimi Tainong No. 6
フィールドテストではホンライミ タイノン 6 号を使用します。
Taichung No. 9 and Taichung First No. 10
台中9号と台中第一10号
Then you can see that this is
そうすれば、これが
It is the strength and weakness of the disease I showed you earlier.
それは先ほど示した病気の長所と短所です。
Then this is if you have been on Tainong No. 67, you can see that this is for curing diseases
では、これは太農67号に乗ったことがあれば、これが病気を治すためのものであることがわかるでしょう
Then you just need to spread the righteousness of our handsome
それなら、私たちのハンサムな正義を広めるだけでいいのです
It is more resistant to disease
病気に強くなります
So whether it is Tainong No. 67, Taycan No. 9, or Taichung Line to No. 10, it can be used
そのため、台濃67号でも、台缶9号でも、台中線から10号でも利用できます。
So we have this
それで、これがあります
Now we are talking with Xinnong to discuss whether it is how we want to mass produce
現在、私たちはそれが量産したい方法であるかどうかについてXinnongと話し合っています。
Then with this creature, plus teacher Wang Qiangsheng’s anti-Baiyuegu disease waterway
この生き物と、王強生先生の白月谷病対策の水路
I think we have solved the problem of white moon solid disease in Taiwan in the next 10 or 20 years
今後10年か20年で台湾の白月固体病の問題は解決すると思います
You don't need pesticides, just plant the anti-white moon disease water channel of Mr. Wang Qiangsheng
農薬は必要ありません、王強生氏の白月病予防用水路を植えるだけです。
Then at the right time, especially after Taiwan, you spread our Shangqing justice
そして、適切なタイミングで、特に台湾の後、あなたは私たちの上清の正義を広めました
Probably no need for pesticides
おそらく農薬は必要ないと思われます
So this probably isn't
だからこれはおそらくそうではない
that is
あれは
If it is to say that the direction of our research in the early stage of the Hospital of Traditional Chinese Medicine
中医病院の初期段階における私たちの研究の方向性と言えば
we probably wouldn't do this kind of question
おそらくこの種の質問はしないでしょう
But because we are called agricultural biotechnology
しかし、私たちは農業バイオテクノロジーと呼ばれているので、
if you go to that sky
あの空へ行くなら
you will find that there are many problems
多くの問題があることがわかるでしょう
In fact, you can pay equal attention to applied and basic science
実際、応用科学と基礎科学に同じように注意を払うことができます。
This is a good example
これは良い例です
The researchers at the Chinese hospital are not capable of doing all of them.
中国の病院の研究者はそれらすべてを行うことができるわけではない。
You see our team actually has a neutral university
ほら、私たちのチームには実際には中立的な大学があります
National Taiwan University, especially the department of agronomy
国立台湾大学、特に農学部
There is also a farm
農園もあります
Not only did we do this
私たちがこれをやっただけではありません
This is just one of our seven sub-plans
これは 7 つのサブプランのうちの 1 つにすぎません
The existing achievements of the two sub-projects
2つのサブプロジェクトのこれまでの成果
Teacher Qiu Zizhen's team
邱紫鎮先生のチーム
And teacher Cai Yifang's team
そして蔡宜芳先生のチーム
They actually found the same picture library inside
彼らは実際に同じ画像ライブラリを内部で見つけました
find something called i cant call it a picture gallery
写真ギャラリーとは言えない、何かを見つけてください
new strain
新しい株
You give him very little respite and he very little fade
あなたは彼にほんの少しの休息を与えても、彼はほとんど衰えません
He looks just like you, give him a lot of flashbacks, a lot of flashbacks
彼はあなたにそっくりです、たくさんフラッシュバックしてください、たくさんフラッシュバックしてください
exactly as good
まさに同じくらい良い
So now they're working on
そこで彼らは今取り組んでいます
why did you give him so little fading
なぜ彼にそれほど色褪せを与えなかったのですか
he can look just as good
彼も同じくらい良く見えるよ
This is actually a very difficult problem
これは実はとても難しい問題です
But Teacher Qiu Zizhen and Teacher Cai Yifang are probably world-class
しかし、Qiu Zizhen先生とCai Yifang先生はおそらく世界クラスです
two of the best scientists in plant nutrition
植物栄養学の最高の科学者二人
so i want to give them a few more years
だから彼らにはあと数年与えたい
It should be possible not only to say that it is practical
実用的であるだけでなく、
can go to the fields
畑に行ける
It is also possible to understand the molecular mechanism
分子機構も理解できる
So to say I think I'm on this team I think we
つまり、私はこのチームについて考えていると思います、私たちはそう思います
We can't say we've reached it
到達したとは言えません
In other words, I think our original idea
つまり、私たちの本来のアイデアは、
is to build a platform
プラットフォームを構築することです
so we can have a quick
簡単に
that has the ability to quickly produce new strains
新しい株を素早く生み出す能力がある
So I gave a speech at the Council of Agriculture last month
そこで私は先月農業審議会で講演をしました
Speaking of Agricultural Economics
農業経済といえば
is how you bring technology into this molecular domain
この分子領域にテクノロジーを導入する方法です
Then there is an expert from Japan
それから日本から専門家が来ます
He said their plan now is to have vegetables or rice
彼は、彼らの今の計画は野菜か米を食べることだと言いました
They estimate if they have a letter of need to develop
開発が必要な通知書があるかどうかを見積もる
They do it about every three years
彼らは約3年ごとにそれを行います
The Mutual Aid Committee of the Council of Agriculture said whether we have the ability to do it
農業審議会の共済委員会は、私たちにそれができるかどうかと言った。
i think we have
私たちは持っていると思います
but one thing is important
でも一つ重要なことがある
You need what's called a gene bank
遺伝子バンクと呼ばれるものが必要です
Because of the resistance I just mentioned
さっき言った抵抗のせいで
In fact, there are more or less in nature
実際、自然界には多かれ少なかれ、
So why do you ask why biology makes sex important
ではなぜ生物学がセックスを重要視するのかを尋ねるのはなぜですか
It's that you have to keep the genetic pool of these resistances in the gene pool
つまり、これらの耐性を遺伝子プール内に保持しなければなりません
then when you need
それから必要なときに
You can go to the resistance genes that are already there in nature
自然界にすでに存在する耐性遺伝子にアクセスできます
You just smash it with the method of molecular domain
分子ドメインの手法で叩き潰すだけだ
to what you need
必要なものに
so why do we do
ではなぜそうするのか
Although we are doing so-called biotechnology
いわゆるバイオテクノロジーをやっているのですが、
You still have to support the so-called Bio-Diversity
いわゆる生物多様性を依然としてサポートする必要があります
Because this is direction interlocking
方向連動なので
you must have gene pool
遺伝子プールが必要です
The gene bank is Bio-Diversity
遺伝子バンクは生物多様性です
Use the mutant gene pool with you
変異遺伝子プールを活用しましょう
So why can we be so successful now
では、なぜ今これほど成功することができるのでしょうか
Because the farm has established a very good
農場は非常に優れた環境を確立しているため、
That mutant library is over there
あのミュータント図書館はあそこにある
And the waterway has a lot of natural ones
そして水路には自然がたくさんあります
That mutant walks over there
あのミュータントがあそこを歩く
So the channel is very thick
チャネルが非常に厚いため、
Should be pretty easy now
今ではかなり簡単になるはずです
Can be used as wedding paper
ウェディングペーパーとしても使えます
Most of that resistance has
その抵抗のほとんどは、
That
それか
So I guess it's almost time
ということで、もうそろそろ時間だと思います
then i think
それから私は思います
I listened to Shen Zheng Yuyan City last month
先月はShen Zheng Yuyan Cityを聴きました
his that
彼のそれ
There is a last era
最後の時代がある
i think i'm going to steal it and use it
盗んで使おうと思う
He said Taiwanese people are not afraid
台湾人は怖くないと彼は言った
say because of you
あなたのせいで言う
you have a difficult problem
あなたは難しい問題を抱えています
you think you can't solve
あなたは解決できないと思っていますか
He means you just need to put your mind to it
彼が言いたいのは、ただそれに集中するだけでいいということ
With the waywardness of us Taiwanese, we must do it
私たち台湾人のわがままで、それをしなければなりません
Although I have told you so much before
先ほどもたくさんお伝えしましたが、
our policy issues
私たちの政策問題
Easy policy seems to be messed up
安易な政策はめちゃくちゃになりそうだ
a series of that is
それのシリーズ
It is the evil law I mentioned earlier.
それが先ほど述べた悪法です。
But in fact those evil laws
しかし実際にはそれらの悪法は
The benefits of deferment aren't that bad
延期のメリットはそこまで悪くない
that now is to
それは今です
if we find a way
方法が見つかったら
be able to put these policies
これらのポリシーを立てることができる
change it up a bit
少し変えてみる
Let us plan the sustainable development of Taiwan's agriculture
台湾農業の持続可能な発展を計画しましょう
Average person goals and execution strategies
平均的な個人の目標と実行戦略
Then this must be driven by the government
だったらこれは政府主導で進めるべきだ
because without the government
なぜなら政府がなければ
you are really
あなたは本当に
you with the power of the people
あなたは人々の力で
absolutely impossible
絶対に無理
There must be a good government
良い政府がなければなりません
The second is the participation of the people
２つ目は国民の参加です
The people are us, you and me
人々は私たち、あなた、そして私です
I think many people have seen this question more or less in the newspapers.
この質問は多かれ少なかれ新聞などで目にしたことがある方も多いと思います。
Like last month, some people protested against the constitutional government in Yilan
先月と同様、宜蘭でも憲政政府に抗議する人々がいた
Several teachers from Yilan University started to organize
宜蘭大学の数人の教師が組織を始めた
Hold forums and give speeches in various places in Yilan
宜蘭各地でフォーラムや講演会を開催
If you can’t have only one voice in Taiwanese society
台湾社会でたった一つの声しか持てないなら
Everyone should be able to organize
誰もが整理できるはずです
Let the public know your ideas
あなたのアイデアを世間に知らせましょう
I think this is the responsibility of us scholars in traditional Chinese medicine hospitals and everyone else.
これは私たち中医病院の学者をはじめとするすべての人々の責任だと思います。
That is, you have to participate in this kind of social
つまり、この種のソーシャルに参加する必要があります
In fact, it cannot be called a problem that society is closely related to us.
実は社会が私たちと密接に関わっていることは問題とは言えません。
Then why do I say Taiwanese
ではなぜ台湾人だと言うのか
You are not afraid, because in fact our agricultural technology in Taiwan
心配する必要はありません。実際、私たちの農業技術は台湾にあります。
World class at least so far
少なくともこれまでのところワールドクラス
It's just that we didn't integrate it
それを統合していないだけです
Everyone, if you look at the pumpkin industry
皆さん、かぼちゃ業界を見てみると
know we didn't rely on
私たちが依存していなかったことを知っています
In fact, we grow pumpkins
実はうちでもカボチャを栽培しています
And what about the pumpkin production line?
ではカボチャの生産ラインはどうでしょうか？
rarely rely on the government
政府に頼ることはほとんどない
It's all our small farmers and some
それはすべて私たちの小規模農家とその一部です
that pumpkin lover
あのカボチャ好きな人
I have to build it up slowly by myself to get to the current scale.
今の規模に到達するには、自分でゆっくりと作り上げていかなければなりません。
Taiwan is now exporting Butterfly South for one year
台湾は現在、Butterfly Southを1年間輸出しています
About four billion Taiwan dollars
約40億台湾ドル
That feeds a lot of people
それは多くの人に栄養を与えます
And it won't happen suddenly
そして、それは突然起こるわけではありません
what they did
彼らが何をしたのか
Although some will be brought to the mainland by Taiwanese businessmen
一部は台湾の実業家によって本土に持ち込まれることになるが
also hard to go
行きにくい
But some skills cannot be learned
ただし習得できないスキルもある
Because like the pumpkin now that link
だって今のリンクはカボチャのように
by tissue culture
組織培養による
Taiwan's organization training is
台湾の組織研修は
nothing happened in doing
やっても何も起こらなかった
not what you hire college students for
大学生を雇う目的ではない
it is a production line
それは生産ラインです
rarely infected
まれに感染する
big german family
ドイツ人の大家族
multinational
多国籍
go to vietnam to do
するためにベトナムに行きます
He also wants to follow the example of Taiwan
彼はまた、台湾の例に倣いたいと考えている
he built a big
彼は大きなものを建てた
tissue cultured
組織培養された
he closed after three years
彼は3年後に閉店した
because he can't
彼にはできないから
There is no way for the value of other functions
他の関数の値を取得する方法はありません
In fact, tissue culture
実際、組織培養は
hard to say
言いにくい
It's not easy to say
言うのは簡単ではありません
But the one in Taiwan
でも台湾のものは
Farmers also do these
農家もこんなことやってるよ
Agricultural Values
農業の価値観
He just has his unique place
彼には自分のユニークな場所があるだけだ
like our hurricane grapes
ハリケーン・グレープのように
Everyone can know
誰もが知ることができる
The ones grown in Taiwan are all good
台湾産はどれも美味しい
And now grapes
そして今はブドウ
all year round, right?
一年中ですよね？
Grapes are actually seasonal.
実はブドウには季節があります。
That's because our farmers in Taiwan
それは台湾の農家がいるからです。
know when
いつわかるか
with appropriate feedback
適切なフィードバックとともに
You can adjust
調整できます
make it bloom
咲かせる
that technology
その技術
already arrived
すでに到着しています
Because they come to Taiwan to study
彼らは台湾に留学しに来ているので、
But they still can't make as good grapes
しかし、彼らはまだそれほど良いブドウを作ることができません
Because of the problem of pests and diseases
害虫や病気の問題があるので、
There is no country in the world where farmers
農家がいる国は世界中にない
Have the patience to bag
忍耐強くバッグに入れてください
Guys, did you see that bag
皆さん、そのバッグを見ましたか？
he is a worker
彼は労働者です
If you ask mainland farmers to do it, they won’t do it
本土の農民にそれをやれと言ったら、彼らはやってくれない
So why can we reduce pesticides
ではなぜ農薬を減らすことができるのでしょうか
make fruit that can be so beautiful
とても美しい果物を作る
because we farmers
私たち農家だから
He not only has this technique
彼はこの技術を持っているだけではありません
There is still this patience that can be done
まだできる忍耐力はあります
So our
それで私たちの
Even though the day before yesterday on the front line
一昨日も最前線にいたのに
And to our research on agricultural technology
そして農業技術の研究へ
We actually have a good chance
実は我々には良いチャンスがある
Now that's when we take advantage of it
今こそそれを活用するときです
Then let us Taiwan's agriculture
それでは台湾の農業を見てみましょう
sustainable development
持続可能な発展
ok i think i will stop here
わかりました、ここでやめておこうと思います
Thanks
ありがとう
and i want to thank my team
そしてチームに感謝したいです
It's definitely not my job alone
それは間違いなく私一人の仕事ではありません
Thanks also to our Academia Sinica
中央研究院にも感謝します
Fellow Science Center support
フェローサイエンスセンターのサポート
There is also the Council of Agriculture and their investigation of the Agricultural Experimental Institute
農業審議会とその農業試験場に関する調査もあります。
They are really very generous to us
彼らは本当に私たちにとても寛大です
Whatever we use they are absolutely unconditionally fair
私たちが何を使用しても、それらは完全に無条件に公平です
so it's very good
だからとても良いです
I think it is a good platform
良いプラットフォームだと思う
because the whole is a joke
全部冗談だから
And the cooperation with Kua Unit
そしてクアユニットとの連携
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Thank you Director Shi
史監督、ありがとう
Very macro and micro
非常にマクロとミクロ
sounds very exciting
とても刺激的ですね
If you can't do it anymore, do you have any questions to ask him?
もうそれができないなら、彼に何か質問はありますか？
Come
来て
middle button
真ん中のボタン
Thank you very much Mr. Shi for your wonderful speech
Shi先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
We also learned a lot here
私たちもここでたくさんのことを学びました
In the Prime Minister's speech just now
先ほどの総理の演説の中で
I probably have three
たぶん3つ持ってる
As I said, the sustainable development of Taiwan is closely related to the loss of high-quality translations
先ほども述べたように、台湾の持続可能な発展は、高品質の翻訳の喪失と密接に関係しています。
The second zero profit and weakness of high-quality agricultural policy
第二のゼロ利益と質の高い農業政策の弱点
The third is the cultivation of high-quality talents and the education of a disadvantaged one.
3つ目は、質の高い人材の育成と恵まれない人材の教育です。
These three are actually related to a free relationship, that is, a person with talent.
この3つは実は自由な関係、つまり才能のある人と関係しています。
Here are two questions to ask Mr. Shi
Shi 氏に尋ねたい 2 つの質問です。
first question please
最初の質問をお願いします
If your money is on May 20 next year, my colleague Dalin Hung
あなたのお金が来年 5 月 20 日なら、私の同僚、ダリン・フン
If Luzumi Nakato has a third floor
もし中戸ルズミに3階があったら
What do you think is the market impact on the sustainable development of Taiwan's agriculture?
台湾農業の持続可能な発展に対する市場の影響は何だと思いますか?
The second question is do you have any way to influence your money, colleague Dalin Hung
2番目の質問は、同僚のダリン・フンさん、自分のお金に影響を与える方法はありますか？
because we know his expertise is in public
彼の専門知識が公に公開されていることを私たちは知っているからです
game development for farming
農業向けゲーム開発
What kind of positive impact can you put forward and provide him with advice, thank you
あなたは彼にどのようなプラスの影響を与えることができますか、アドバイスを提供していただけますか、ありがとう
right
右
ok i think i can answer one step
わかりました、一歩答えられると思います
i think chen hu is my immediate boss
チェン・フーが私の直属の上司だと思う
I interact with him a lot
私は彼とよく交流します
I believe he has a strong interest in the sustainable development of Taiwan's agriculture
彼は台湾農業の持続可能な発展に強い関心を持っていると思います
There must be a positive impact
必ず良い影響があるはずです
Now it means
今、それは意味します
we have a plan
私たちには計画があります
is helping with this
これを手伝ってくれています
the rural back state problem
田舎の裏州問題
Chen Hu is leading
チェン・フーがリード
So he is concerned about agricultural issues
だから彼は農業問題を懸念している
know very well
とてもよく知っています
So I think he will give
だから彼はくれると思うよ
That is to say, if Tsai Ing-wen is elected
つまり蔡英文さんが当選したら
he must be a good host
彼は良いホストに違いない
Then the second one will I have any influence
じゃあ二番目は私が何か影響を与えるだろうか
then i will tell two stories
それでは2つの話をします
My wife heard that Chen Jianren was nominated for vice president
妻は陳建仁氏が副総統に指名されたと聞いた
He said you stay away from him
彼はあなたが彼から遠ざかると言った
Then the second is
それから 2 つ目は、
I told Dean Li some of my methods
私はディーン・リーに私のメソッドのいくつかを話しました
That is, how to enforce these policies
つまり、これらのポリシーをどのように実施するかということです。
my wife said you go
妻があなたが行くと言った
Brass less than a month
真鍮 1ヶ月未満
Dean Li said you don't get a week without Lars
ディーン・リーはラースなしでは一週間も持たないと言った
so i think
だから私は思う
What I mean by this is
これが何を意味するかというと、
need a comparison
比較が必要です
How can... a person like Chengwu
成武のような人がどうして...
he may stand
彼は立つかもしれない
we need a good
私たちには良いものが必要です
Chairman of the Council of Agriculture
農業評議会議長
but he needs to have
しかし彼にはそれが必要です
Political School
政治学校
Can manage our legislative chambers
立法院を管理できる
I think the biggest problem is the legislation
最大の問題は法律だと思う
then this legislation
それからこの法律
Then the administrative law I mentioned
それから、私が申し上げた行政法は、
Probably as long as you have a good county magistrate
おそらく、優秀な郡判事がいる限り、
It is indeed possible to execute
確かに実行可能です
but to get to the bottom of it
しかし、その根底に到達するには
You want a permanent agricultural basic law
恒久的な農業基本法が必要だ
that's probably
それはおそらく
but our legislature
しかし私たちの立法府は
In fact, I read the papers to propose bills.
実は私も法案を提案するために新聞を読みました。
So if you can be brave
だから勇気を出せるなら
not brave
勇敢ではない
Actively participate in this kind of worship
このような礼拝に積極的に参加しましょう
you can disagree with me
あなたは私に同意できません
But I think we're right about this...
しかし、これについては私たちが正しいと思います...
be more concerned
もっと心配してください
because we've all heard the farmhouse problem
農家の問題は誰もが聞いたことがあるからです
but you rarely hear
でもめったに聞きません
There are people in Taipei who are openly discussing this issue
台北にはこの問題について公然と議論している人たちがいる
So I think this is the participation of our society
これが私たちの社会の参加だと思います
I think the most important
最も重要だと思います
Because the Legislative Yuan almost relies on public opinion to govern the country
立法院は国を統治するのにほぼ世論に依存しているため
so you just let them know it's an important issue
それで、それが重要な問題であることを彼らに知らせるだけです
people are paying attention
人々は注目しています
to ask
聞く、質問する
I am New Deal Company
私はニューディール会社です
My name is Lin
我姓林
hello please sit down
こんにちは、座ってください
ask now
今すぐ尋ねてください
There used to be a Kaohsiung 131
昔は高雄131もあった
This seems good too
これも良さそうです
How does it compare to this
これと比べてどうですか
And our company has introduced this Ye Guangming
そして、当社はこの葉光明を導入しました
This is Yan Tian's
こちらはヤンティアンさんです
farming
農業
there is a peasant association
農民組合がある
Everyone has peasant officials and citizens
誰にでも農民役人や国民がいる
We introduce them
それらを紹介します
and then this
それからこれ
There is Semite in California
カリフォルニアにはセミテがある
there is a us taiwanese
私たち台湾人がいます
their American company
彼らのアメリカの会社
He is Hong Xinxiong
彼はホン・シンションです
he is a doctor
彼は医者です
where he produces people
彼が人を生み出す場所
The rice on his side is called national defense rice
彼の味方の米は国防米と呼ばれる
It is given to Japanese geniuses every year
毎年日本の天才に贈られる
I have lived in other homes several times
何度か他の家に住んだことがある
this person is very nice
この人はとてもいい人です
But he is also a doctor
しかし彼は医者でもあります
Then there is a banquet in Japan recently
それから最近日本で宴会があります
Water Pressure Yunmei
水圧ユンメイ
This is inside our pentagon
ここは五角形の内側です
Some here are good
ここのいくつかは良いです
It's not good here, he's not, he's really good
ここは良くない、彼は違う、彼は本当に良い
I want to take his original seed, but he won't give it to me
彼の元の種を取りたいのですが、彼はそれをくれません
He said, don't sell but fix
彼は言った、売るのではなく修理せよ
He became patented, not as easy as Moonlight Rice
彼は特許を取得したが、ムーンライトライスほど簡単ではなかった
So there's this synopsis aspect
このような概要の側面があります
see what they do
彼らが何をするか見てください
this tastes good too, what
これも美味しいです、何ですか？
Comfort, and this certificate, and this processing can all be done
心地よさもこの証明書もこの加工も全部できる
It seems that this favorite music is the best in Japan at present
この好きな音楽が今日本で一番いいらしい
This, sorry, I say this to
これ、ごめんなさい、これを言うのは
I know, I know, thank you, thank you, because
わかってる、わかってる、ありがとう、ありがとう、だって
I think that there should be different strains in different places.
さまざまな場所にさまざまな系統があっていいと思います。
As for Moonlight Rice, there should be several strains in Taiwan
月光米に関しては、台湾にいくつかの品種があるはずです。
One of the strains, if I remember correctly
私の記憶が正しければ、株の1つ
If you go to Japan, you should have won the moonlight rice
日本に行くなら月光米を獲得すべきだった
I won the moonlight rice in the previous year's competition last year
昨年の大会では月光米で優勝しました
so they
ので
It's the weird rice you mentioned
それはあなたが言っていた奇妙な形のお米です
Mr. Wang Qiangsheng
王強生氏
i suggest you visit the farm
農場を訪れることをお勧めします
He planted all his mutant species over there.
彼はすべての突然変異種をそこに植えました。
Then you even saw the very one
それからあなたはまさにそのものを見ました
What do you guys appreciate most now?
皆さんは今何が一番好きですか？
Antioxidants?
抗酸化物質？
There's the red one over there, and the paper one.
あそこに赤いのと紙のやつがあります。
So that mutation bank over there is really good.
つまり、そこにあるミュータントライブラリは本当に優れています。
Then you and him are also related
そうするとあなたも彼も血縁関係にあるのですね
Now their Council of Agriculture is also developing some rice
現在、彼らの農業評議会もいくつかの米を開発しています。
come for viewing
見に来てください
Because its leaf shape is very beautiful
葉っぱの形がとても綺麗なので
Then I believe that if you plug carefully
慎重に接続すれば、
It should be encouraged and there are beautiful ones
それは奨励されるべきであり、美しいものもあります
so it's a pity
だから残念だ
because if you come to my church last week
なぜなら、もしあなたが先週私の教会に来たら
Because of the farm
因為農事所
The one celebrating his 120th anniversary this week and last weekend
今週と先週末で生誕120周年を祝う
So he got all his babies out
それで彼は赤ちゃんを全員外に連れ出した
Exhibited in his farm
彼の農場に展示されました
That
それか
we don't give him business
私たちは彼に仕事を与えません
OK, let me ask the Council of Agriculture again
では、もう一度農業審議会に質問させていただきます。
Because they usually have the one with the international waterway
国際水路のあるものが多いので
ok, we don't give it to us
わかりました、私たちには与えません
good
良い
those two words
その二つの言葉
So Feast , Feast of Feast
そうだ、饗宴、饗宴の饗宴
Restraining harm is Yankee
危害を抑えるのはヤンキー
Banquet
バンケット
good
良い
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
ok, here you go
わかりました、ここに来てください
I charge a lot for your speeches
あなたのスピーチに多額の料金を請求します
but your final conclusion
しかしあなたの最終的な結論は
I feel like there is a contradiction
矛盾があるような気がする
You said the government led the people to participate in
あなたは政府が国民に参加するよう指導したと言いました
this is the first day
今日が初日です
The second is whether you have talked about
2つ目は、次のことについて話したかどうかです。
Orchids, lots of fruit
蘭、果物がたくさん
It's all made by the farmers themselves
全て農家さん自らが作ったものです
nothing to do with the government
政府とは何の関係もありません
Aren't these two contradictory?
この二つは矛盾していませんか？
OK
OK
ours
私たちのもの
Okay, let's take orchids as an example.
さて、蘭を例に挙げてみましょう。
The output value of our orchids is 4 billion
私たちの蘭の生産額は40億ドルです
Compared with the electronics industry
エレクトロニクス業界と比べて
A piece of cake
朝飯前
When I came back in 2010
2010年に戻ってきたとき
Back in 2008 2009
2008年に戻る 2009年
heard something
何かを聞いた
Varma of America
ヴァルマ・オブ・アメリカ
order
注文
Flower farmers in Taiwan
台湾の花農家
the one that supplies him with varmas all over america
アメリカ全土に彼にヴァルマを供給する者
If we eat this order
この注文を食べたら
That's about a few decades
それからおそらく数十年
Our output value is definitely more than four billion
私たちの生産額は間違いなく40億を超えています
but why do we
しかし、なぜ私たちは
Because we are not an agribusiness
私たちはアグリビジネスではないので、
we are small farmers
私たちは小さな農家です
they may have some alliances
彼らは何らかの同盟を結んでいるかもしれない
so i think
だから私は思う
First our government does not have one
まず、私たちの政府にはそれがありません
What kind of venture capital fund do we have?
どのようなベンチャーキャピタルファンドがありますか?
We don't have an agricultural venture fund
農業ベンチャーファンドはありません
Council of Agriculture asks the government
農業委員会が政府に要請
Asked for at least back from me
少なくとも私からの返事を求められました
We meet every year at the Council of Agriculture
私たちは毎年農業評議会で会合を持っています
we both say it takes
私たちは二人ともそれが必要だと言います
just don't have this fund
この資金がないだけです
Now there is a biomedical start-up fund
現在、生物医学のスタートアップファンドが設立されています
But there is no farming
でも農業は無い
so like this
だからこのように
to become an agribusiness
アグリビジネスになるために
I think it's still a government policy
まだ政府の方針だと思う
We want a school of appearance
見た目の学校が欲しい
So what we have now is wonderful
だから私たちが今持っているものは素晴らしいです
correct
正しい
but you have to deal with the future
しかし、あなたは未来に対処しなければなりません
i think there is still a problem
まだ問題があると思います
the second is
2番目は
I said the government should drive
私は政府が運転すべきだと言いました
Then compare the above policy aspects
次に、上記のポリシーの側面を比較します
allocation of land and water
土地と水の配分
i think this has no government
ここには政府がないと思う
It's useless for you to do it tomorrow
明日やっても無駄だよ
I'm talking about government-led
私が言っているのは政府主導のことです
we are involved in this
私たちはこれに関わっています
you want to be big
あなたは大きくなりたいですか
No, I mean that the first item and the second item you mentioned just now are contradictory
いや、今おっしゃった第一項と第二項は矛盾しているということです。
Yeah
うん
I totally agree with your first item that the government leads the people to participate
政府が国民の参加を主導するという最初の項目に完全に同意します
That is, our government does not pay much attention to agriculture at present.
つまり、私たちの政府は現在、農業にあまり関心を払っていません。
It is the carving of faces in rural areas that creates many, many problems
田舎での顔の彫刻は多くの問題を引き起こします
uh-huh
うん
The funding for the research units of the agricultural institute you mentioned is not enough.
あなたが言及した農業研究所の研究部門への資金は十分ではありません。
right
右
Many comparative research centers are also shrinking
多くの比較研究センターも縮小している
All the things in the research center are gone
研究センターにあったものはすべてなくなった
right
右
So you say the government leads the people to participate in
つまり、政府が国民に参加するよう指導していると言うのですね。
This may have a higher class
こちらのほうが高級かも知れません
That is, we want a good government, good representatives of public opinion, good representatives of public opinion
つまり、私たちは良い政府、良い世論の代表、良い世論の代表を望んでいます。
or else
それとも
In my idea, the government should be a good government
私の考えでは、政府は良い政府であるべきです
But there are always times of disappointment
でも、がっかりする時も必ずある
right
右
ok
Ok
Occidental, personal matters are subject to thank you
偶然の個人的な事柄は感謝の対象となります
i want to ask two questions
2つの質問がしたいです
The first is that you just mentioned that
1つ目は、今おっしゃったことです。
In terms of waterways
水路でいえば
backcross
バッククロス
this will take four years
これには4年かかります
Then if in terms of genetic modification
では、遺伝子組み換えに関して言えば、
can shorten the period of this backcross
この戻し交雑の期間を短縮することができます
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
the second is
2番目は
Like the new varieties we pre-assessed
事前に評価した新品種と同様
That one is made in the improvement factory
あれは改良工場で作られています
it's just a handful
それはほんの一握りです
I am always thinking
私はいつも考えています
how does it expand to
それはどのように拡張されますか
Let the whole province's rice be replanted
道全体の米を改植させましょう
how did this expand
これはどのように拡張されましたか
OK
OK
i think in general
一般的には思います
if you understand
もし分かれば
For example, what are we going to fight against?
たとえば、何と戦うのでしょうか？
anti-what mechanism
反何のメカニズム
you usually just want
あなたは通常ただ欲しいだけです
Do 10,000 basic research first
まずは基礎研究を10,000件行う
Then after knowing the mechanism
そしてそのメカニズムを知った上で、
which gene do you know
どの遺伝子を知っていますか
Of course you have this basis in the future
もちろん、将来的にはこの基礎が得られます
do genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えをする
much faster in some crops
一部の作物でははるかに速くなります
But not now for waterways
しかし、今は水路ではそうではありません
Because rice, for example, if I just want to find
だって、例えばお米を見つけたいだけなら
Rice is the same as rice because it has many species
お米は種類が多いからお米と同じ
So it has this resistance
それでこの抵抗があります
So it's not that you have to do genetic modification
遺伝子組み換えをしなければならないというわけではありません
That is to say, after you enter, we call it T1, the first generation
つまり、入った後はT1、つまり初代と呼ばれます。
You can't use the first generation because it's actually mixed
初代は実は混在しているので使えません
You have fortified for generations
あなたは何世代にもわたって強化してきました
So genetic modification is not available in the first generation
したがって、第一世代では遺伝子組み換えは利用できません
i know what you mean
あなたが言っていることがわかります
Of course the GMO will be irreplaceable at some point
もちろんGMOはいつかは代替不可能なものになるだろう
because you have like a banana
あなたはバナナのようなものを持っているから
Bananas you can't do crossbreeding
バナナは交配ができない
Bananas reproduce asexually
バナナは無性生殖します
So you have to improve its traits
したがって、その特性を改善する必要があります
The fastest you can do it with GM bananas
GMバナナを使えば最速でできる
so you
だからあなたは
My felacephy is to say
私のフェラセフィーが言いたいのは、
when possible
可能であれば
you use monocular breathing
あなたは単眼呼吸を使っています
that is if possible
それは可能であれば
when necessary
必要に応じて
when you must
しなければならないとき
use genetic energy
用genetic energy
Personally, I absolutely believe that genetic modification is very safe.
個人的には、遺伝子組み換えは非常に安全であると絶対に信じています。
But because it's not already a scientific question
しかし、それはすでに科学的な問題ではないため、
it's a political issue it's a social issue
それは政治問題です、それは社会問題です
So you are here to take our scientist's point of view
あなたは私たちの科学者の観点を理解するためにここに来ました
you have to solve the problem
あなたは問題を解決しなければなりません
And you have to be able to make it easy for ordinary people to accept
そして一般の人にも受け入れられやすくする必要があります
So the fastest way is to use monocular breathing
したがって、最も早い方法は単眼呼吸を使用することです
Everyone wouldn't have that pattern
誰もがそのパターンではないでしょう
But genetically modified things must be done
しかし、遺伝子組み換えは行わなければなりません
because you have many places
たくさんの場所があるから
You can't do it with a traditional molecule
従来の分子ではそれはできません
so here is my opinion
ここに私の意見があります
There is also a second question
2 番目の質問があります
What is done and then given out after
何が行われ、その後に渡されるのか
how can you do it
どうすればそれができますか
Our Council of Agriculture has a
私たちの農業評議会には、
It is our Taiwan agriculture
それが私たちの台湾農業です
That is to say, a place where the agricultural system is very complete
つまり、農業システムが非常に充実している場所です。
they will
彼らはそうするだろう
So the farm reform factory is in direct contact with the farmers
だから農業改革工場は農家と直接コミュニケーションをとっています
Then everywhere they will know
そうすればどこでも彼らは知ることになるでしょう
Rice will grow better in this place because of its water and soil
水と土があるこの場所ではお米がよく育ちます
Therefore, the agricultural reform factory will recommend farmers
そこで農業改革ファクトリーは農家さんにオススメします
That is to say, you go to plant a strain
つまり、株を植えに行きます
So why are the Taiwan stalks planted on Chishang?
では、なぜ池上に台湾の茎が植えられているのでしょうか？
And now most of the west coast plants are Tainong No. 71
そして現在、西海岸の植物のほとんどは Tainong No. 71 です。
So there are agricultural reform factories that are responsible for these aspects
したがって、これらの側面を担当する農業改革工場があります
So we have the Council of Agriculture and this kind of policy of withdrawal
それで、私たちは農業評議会とこの種の撤退政策を持っています
and always
そして、いつも
so the system is very good
システムはとても良いので
ask that
それを尋ねてください
consult
相談する
Spars
スパー
I just heard you say that machine modification is safe? Is it true?
機械の改造は安全だと聞いたのですが本当ですか?
I am afraid that the so-called tofu will be broken
壊れるのが怖いいわゆる豆腐
Dare to eat it? Is it really safe?
食べてみませんか?本当に安全ですか?
Actually you
実はあなた
Because of genetic modification, everyone is afraid that you have introduced foreign genes, right?
遺伝子組み換えということで、外来遺伝子が入ってしまったのではないかとみんな心配していますよね？
do you eat flour
小麦粉を食べますか
do you know where that wheat comes from
その小麦がどこから来たのか知っていますか
do beans matter
豆は重要ですか
without me talking about flour first
私が最初に小麦粉について話さずに
wheat you know
ご存知小麦
He is an extended species but he introduced
彼は拡張種ですが、導入されました
Didn't know there were three different breeds of genes
遺伝子に3つの異なる品種があるとは知りませんでした
So he's a mix of a lot of alien genes
つまり、彼は多くのエイリアンの遺伝子が混ざり合っているのです
So the genetically modified crops are actually just introducing a
つまり、遺伝子組み換え作物は実際には、
a foreign gene or two
外来遺伝子の 1 つか 2 つ
Well, in fact, you don’t need to look at the genes of all genetically modified foods.
実際、すべての遺伝子組み換え食品の遺伝子を調べる必要はありません。
but to look at the safety of his food
しかし、彼の食べ物の安全性を見てください
not only
だけでなく
All countries Taiwan also has a very strict system called
台湾にはどの国にも、と呼ばれる非常に厳格な制度があります。
Food Safety Inspection
食品安全検査
All foods to be marketed for practicality
すべての食品は実用性を重視して販売される
have to go through a series of safety tests
一連の安全性テストを受けなければならない
Until now
今まで
None of the genetically modified
遺伝子組み換えは一切なし
The soy you are talking about and the genetically modified corn
あなたが言及した大豆とGMOトウモロコシ
so there will be insecurity
だから不安もあるだろう
and even if you talk about corn
トウモロコシの話をしても
Genetically Modified Corn Is Likely Safer
遺伝子組み換えトウモロコシの方が安全である可能性が高い
because I promise you if you buy corn
トウモロコシを買ったら約束するから
It will be genetically modified without that insecticide
殺虫剤がなければ遺伝子組み換えされるだろう
or a mess
または混乱
I guarantee you have eaten pesticide
あなたが農薬を食べたことがあると保証します
Much more than genetically modified
遺伝子組み換えをはるかに超えたもの
so you can eat with confidence
安心して食べられるように
I think you've been eating for a long time
ずっと食べてた気がする
because Taiwan
台湾だから
i told you earlier
前に言いました
Taiwan does not import
台湾は輸入しない
do not produce soybeans themselves
大豆自体は生産していない
We import without fainting
めげずに輸入します
You import genetically modified soybeans
遺伝子組み換え大豆を輸入している
GMO soybeans
會基改大豆
We are not such imports
当社はそのような輸入業者ではありません
We import is faint
輸入しているのはかすかな
It depends on his quality, from level one to level ten
それはレベル1からレベル10までの彼の資質に依存します
Then when we grain merchants come in
それから私たち穀物商人が入ってくると、
He doesn't care if you are genetically modified or will be genetically modified
彼はあなたが遺伝子組み換えされているかどうか、またはこれから遺伝子組み換えされるかどうかを気にしません
He started to sell and used the top-level ones as practical
彼は販売を開始し、最高レベルのものを実用的に使用しました
The top low ones are used as animal feed
上の低いものは動物の飼料として使用されます
So any soymilk shop, tofu shop, or even Yiyimi
豆乳屋でも豆腐屋でも、あるいはイーイミでも
I also told you that he will be genetically modified.
彼は遺伝子組み換えされるだろうとも言いました。
he lied to you
彼はあなたに嘘をつきました
he definitely lied to you
彼は間違いなくあなたに嘘をつきました
because you can't avoid
避けることはできないから
Because Taiwan does not produce
台湾は生産してないから
The corn you eat, I guarantee you 100% GMO
あなたが食べるトウモロコシは、100% GMO であることを保証します
because i told you earlier
前に言ったから
Because imported genetically modified corn
遺伝子組み換えトウモロコシが輸入されているため、
you will never eat
あなたは決して食べないでしょう
because it is hard and unpalatable
硬くて不味いから
what you eat what you eat is called
あなたが食べるものをあなたが呼ぶもの あなたが食べるものをあなたが呼ぶもの
Sweet Cone
スイートコーン
corn of utility
実用的なトウモロコシ
Taiwan is 100% self-produced
台湾は100％自社生産
so you should be more careful
だからもっと気をつけるべきだ
Because there are many pesticides
農薬がたくさんあるから
Because corn can easily cause that
トウモロコシはそれを引き起こしやすいので、
and
と
So you are something like this instead
だからあなたは代わりにこのようなものです
you have to wash very
とても洗わなければなりません
soy milk is very safe
豆乳はとても安全です
And I promise you GMOs
そしてGMOについても約束します
he eats naturally
彼は自然に食べる
do you drink soy milk
豆乳を飲みますか
drink
飲む
I can't drink now
もう飲めない
I
私
ah
ああ
here
ここ
good
良い
hello host
こんにちは、ホスト
thank you very much for your speech tonight
今夜のスピーチ、本当にありがとうございました
It is true that there is a lot of harvest
収穫が多いのは事実です
and say you are
そしてあなたはそうだと言う
See Sustainability Issues Inside
内部の持続可能性の問題を参照してください
Because it includes the part of food security
食料安全保障の部分も含まれているので
include
含む
If we say Chinese is food security
中国が食糧安全保障だと言うなら
Only two words of safety
安全の言葉はたった 2 つだけ
But if it's in English
でも英語だと
Security and Safety issues
セキュリティと安全性の問題
you have discussed
あなたは議論しました
So my question is actually
それで、私の質問は実際には
Director Shi has already answered half of the answer just now
施所長は先ほど半分の答えを出しました。
Because you just mentioned that
だってさっき言ったじゃないですか
What we're about to do is
私たちがやろうとしていることは、
A second-generation green revolution
第二世代の緑の革命
because we were in the 1960s
私たちは1960年代にいたから
During the first green revolution
第一次緑の革命のとき
At that time, it was only for the purpose of increasing food production.
当時は食糧増産のみが目的でした。
The extensive use of fertilizers and pesticides
肥料や農薬の多用
but did not consider saying
でも言うことは考えなかった
Problems that follow include pollution
その後に起こる問題には汚染が含まれます
and subsequent generation of some
そしてその後の世代の一部
Farmer's Health Issues
農家の健康問題
The Second Green Revolution
第二次緑の革命
words in your opinion
あなたの意見の言葉
because it involves
関わるからです
also includes bringing a little bit of genetic modification and
遺伝子組み換えを少し導入することも含まれます。
Some more general effects
より一般的な効果
What you just mentioned is that
あなたが今言ったことは、
May reduce dosage
可能減少用量
Reduce environmental pollution
環境汚染の削減
But say whether to consider saying
しかし、言うことを検討するかどうかを言う
If this goes on for a long time in the future
今後もこの状態が長く続くとしたら
will there be
あるだろうか
Speaking in a big environment
大きな環境で話す
Will it be friendly to the environment?
環境に優しいのでしょうか？
Will there be some negative impact
何らかの悪影響はあるでしょうか
including species diversity
種の多様性も含めて
Or those related effects that become harmful
または、有害となる関連する影響
Thanks
ありがとう
i want to answer this question
この質問に答えたい
Avision is relative
ビジョンは相対的なものです
Do you think genetically modified crops will affect biodiversity?
遺伝子組み換え作物は生物多様性に影響を与えると思いますか?
my answer is yes but
私の答えは「はい」ですが、
as long as i feel
私が感じる限り
Since humans have agriculture
人間には農業があるから
as long as you have agricultural land
農地がある限り
no biodiversity
生物多様性がない
Because in nature you don't see
自然の中では見えないから
ten thousand rice fields
一万の水田
rice field
田
ten thousand cornfields
一万のトウモロコシ畑
Then your agriculture for thousands of years in the past few years
そして、過去数年間で何千年も続いた農業
The one that went through pesticides and recycling
農薬とリサイクルを経たもの
Your biological delusions have already
あなたの生物学的妄想はすでに
where people are gone
人がいなくなった場所
So if you say that I plant now
それで、もしあなたが私が今植えると言ったら
This genetically modified vaccine is here
この遺伝子組み換えワクチンはここにあります
Will it affect the delusion of creatures
生き物の妄想に影響を与えるのでしょうか？
you don't exist anymore
あなたはもう存在しません
Because it has been followed by our human behavior
それは私たち人間の行動に従っているからです
Your biological arrogance has long since been destroyed
あなたの生物学的な傲慢さはとっくの昔に破壊されています
Then you have to modify this gene
次に、この遺伝子を変更する必要があります
If planted in the mountains
山に植えると
of course i will affect
もちろん影響します
But you plant ordinary waterways into the mountains
でもあなたは山に普通の水路を植えます
You will affect your ecology as usual
いつものように生態に影響を与えるでしょう
so i think
だから私は思う
That is to say, when you all look at this matter
つまり、皆さんがこの問題を見ると、
I think you must read relative
相対的に読む必要があると思います
That is to say, you are comparing it with the existing agriculture
つまり、既存の農業と比較しているということです。
What are genetically modified crops?
遺伝子組み換え作物とは何ですか?
then i can talk to you
それならあなたと話せます
it is definitely safer
それは間違いなく安全です
And it does less damage to the environment
そして環境へのダメージも少ない
I don't know if this answers your question
これがあなたの質問の答えになるかどうかわかりません
OK
OK
Wang Mu
王武
It's the director. Just now you mentioned the problem of waterway febrile disease.
局長ですよ、今、水路熱性疾患の問題をおっしゃいました。
Then why the previously collected disease strains are relatively complete
では、なぜ以前に収集された病株が比較的完全であるのか
then almost none now
その後、今はほとんどありません
Is it because the brain farmer has used up the opportunity for technology research
ブレイン・ファーマーが技術研究の機会を使い果たしたからでしょうか？
No, this has something to do with our agricultural policy
いいえ、これは我が国の農業政策と関係があります
Didn't we talk about getting some of our
私たちのものを手に入れることについて話しませんでしたか
Humanization of government research units
政府の研究機関の人間化
In that era, there were many soups
あの時代はスープが多かった
And the Banana Research Institute mentioned by Dean Li
そしてリー学部長が言及したバナナ研究所
And the county and city agricultural office, our agricultural cover merchant
そして、県と市の農業局、私たちの農業カバー商人
Many excellent researchers and agricultural talents
優秀な研究者や農業人材が多数
First-line research talents
第一線の研究人材
Move to early retirement or speak badly
早期退職するか悪口を言う
This decade happens to be in turmoil
この10年はたまたま混乱の中にある
it's them who are in turmoil
混乱しているのは彼らだ
To be changed to Cai Tang Chinese
チャイタンチャイニーズに変更予定
When a lot of people can't surrender
多くの人が諦められないとき
Because if you want Cai Tang Chinese
チャイタンの中華料理が欲しいなら
So he wants to use Taitang's point of view
つまり彼はタイタンの視点を利用したいだけなのです
He wants to make a profit
彼は利益を得たいと思っている
so he
彼は
He actually has a Taiwan soup
実は台湾スープもあるんです
In fact, our sugar industry in Taiwan
実際、台湾の砂糖産業は
he is the kingdom
彼は王国です
But then I stopped planting this kind of sugar
でもその後、私はこの種の砂糖を植えるのをやめました
We have a lot of species
たくさんの種がいます
the candy is gone
キャンディーがなくなった
are now in Guangxi
今は広西チワン族自治区にいます
Our Nanhua has many kinds of origin
私たちの南華にはさまざまな起源があります
gone now
もう行ってしまった
because
なぜなら
Just say Cai Tanghua
蔡唐華と言ってください
They feel that they will be humanized by Cai Tang
彼らはCai Tangによって人間化されると感じています
not national
国民的ではない
he won't do it
彼はそれをしません
researchers are
研究者たちは
so i said
だから私は言いました
The collection of physiological data
生理学的データの収集
That decade happened to be
その10年はたまたま
rock the boat
事を荒立てます
In fact, some people said that Cai Tang should be Chinese
実際、蔡唐は中国人であるべきだと言う人もいた
but then it didn't work out
しかしその後はうまくいきませんでした
because of too much resistance
抵抗が多すぎるので
But these ten years
でもこの10年
It's the time when the physiological summary has not been collected
生理学的要約が収集されていない時期です
That
それか
luckily
幸いなことに
Liu Dajiang
劉大江
And the current director once went in
そして、現在のディレクターは一度入った
attach great importance to this
これを非常に重視する
so we start again now
だから今からまた始めよう
Go to various locations in the former province to start collecting
旧州のさまざまな場所に行って収集を開始します
Then Chiayi divides all diseases
それから嘉義はすべての病気を分けます
He is in the special city every year
彼は毎年特別市にいます
So now we are also working on the division of labor
そこで現在は分業化も進めています
Traditional physiological niches are also doing it now
従来の生理学的ニッチ分野でも現在それが行われています
this right
これは正しい
That is to say, I think I should go down later.
つまり、後で下がればいいと思います。
because it will be inherited
受け継がれるから
I am also a member of the Academia Sinica
私は中央研究院の会員でもあります
This is also the owner of this city
この街のオーナーでもある
Member of the Agricultural Center
農業センター会員
I have two words that I want to share with you
あなたに伝えたい言葉が 2 つあります
the first is
一つ目は
Just now the mayor said
先ほど市長が言っていました
our farmers in taiwan
台湾の私たちの農家
This high level is the highest level in the world
このレベルの高さは世界最高レベルです
Dean Li also said just now
ディーン・リーもさっき言いました
His is just a half-open small comment
彼は半分開いた小さなコメントにすぎません
I will share with you
あなたと共有します
three things
三つのこと
Taiwanese farmers
台湾の農民
When participating in the Agricultural Center
農業センターに参加する場合
A Mr. Cai called and said you want to come and see
蔡さんから電話があり、会いに来たいと言われました。
How is our Nanhua planted?
私たちの南華はどのように植えられていますか？
When I went down, I went down with three colleagues in the firm.
私が会社に行くとき、私は会社の同僚3人と一緒に行きました。
What I saw was this factory that was about five times bigger than this room
私が見たのはこの部屋の5倍くらいの広さの工場でした
There is a ditch in front
目の前に溝があります
Make it impossible for ordinary cars to enter
一般車の進入を不可能にする
There are wolf dogs in it
中には狼犬がいる
He said that you people who engage in learning never want to
彼は、学習に従事するあなた方は決して学習を望んでいない、と言いました。
look down on us
私たちを見下して
I'll show you today what we look like
今日は私たちの姿をお見せします
all his techniques
彼のすべてのテクニック
Because I participated in it when I was abroad
海外に行った時に参加したので
Monsanto's so-called most of the research work and so on
モンサント社のいわゆるほとんどの研究活動など
I see their tissue culture
彼らの組織培養が見えます
really world class
本当に世界クラス
But they say we go abroad
でも彼らは私たちが海外に行くと言います
When we came to the Dutch people, they regarded us as bounty soldiers.
私たちがオランダ人のところに来たとき、彼らは私たちを賞金首の兵士だとみなしました。
Now to Taiwan we come back
今度は台湾に戻ります
You are all in college
皆さんは大学生です
nothing never comes
何も来ない
come see us
私たちに会いに来てください
really very embarassing
本当にとても恥ずかしい
just feel ashamed
ただ恥ずかしいと思うだけ
their technical system, etc.
彼らの技術体系など。
still there today
今日もまだそこにいる
so many feathers of our blue flower
私たちの青い花のたくさんの羽
under such circumstances
そのような状況下で
Now that is called seed fate is still there
種の運命と呼ばれるものは今もまだそこにあります
Not only that, it's just a blue flower
それだけではなく、ただの青い花です
Our Taiwan is the one that makes that fish in the world
私たちの台湾は世界でその魚を作っているのです
called invitro fertilization
体外受精といいます
in vitro fertilization
体外受精で
also very powerful
非常に強力でもあります
We in Taiwan can make that grafted plant
台湾の私たちでもその接ぎ木植物を作ることができます
Even the bean sprouts can be grafted
もやしでも接ぎ木できます
So we have these awesome systems
私たちはこれらの素晴らしいシステムを持っています
But it sounds like arguing
でも喧嘩してるみたいだけど
Our government doesn't care
私たちの政府は気にしません
everyone buried there
みんなそこに埋葬されている
Another one is
もう一つは、
I've been thinking about it for a while
しばらく考えていました
Our Agricultural Center
私たちの農業センター
very myself personally at least very anxious
私自身、個人的に少なくとも非常に不安です
We don't seem to have done a single agricultural thing
私たちは農業を何もやっていないようです
Even if you want to do it, you can't do it well
やりたくてもうまくできない
Also since this psychological
また、このような心理的なことから、
Since the benefactor came
恩人が来てくれたので
several years
数年
five or six years
5、6年
get the system out
システムを取り出します
Everyone saw it today
今日はみんなも見たよ
so i feel
だから私は感じます
I won't panic like that
そんなにパニックにはならないよ
OK would not feel like saying
OKとは言いたくないでしょう
what happened
どうしたの
It seems to be these two
この２つらしいです
for your reference
ご参考に
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes, our government is doing something
はい、私たちの政府は何かをしています
that's me
それは私です
Government’s BTC this year
今年の政府のBTC
That's the one
それだ
Every year the government organizes a
政府は毎年、
biotechnology summit
バイオテクノロジーサミット
Then I told the Council of Agriculture
そこで私は農業委員会にこう言いました。
Director Lu Wusheng
監督 ルー・ウーシェン
then we will
それなら私たちはそうします
Together we have planned a
私たちは一緒に計画を立てました
The future is the next five or ten years
未来は5年後か10年後
so-called systems biology
いわゆるシステムバイオロジー
The general description of bringing high technology to Taiwan
台湾へのハイテク導入の概要
Then we lock the top ten
それからトップ 10 を固定します
The top ten general descriptions of Taiwan are
台湾の一般的な説明トップ 10 は次のとおりです。
We use in Taiwan
台湾で使っています
then also
それからまた
Top 10 general descriptions of our competitiveness in the world market
世界市場における当社の競争力の一般的な説明トップ 10
We are going to introduce new technology
新しい技術を導入したい
Establish a so-called industry-government-university-research alliance
いわゆる産官学研究連携の確立
researchers from Academia Sinica
中央研究院の研究者
university researchers
大学研究者
From farmers to farmers we all have a link
農家から農家まで、私たちは皆つながりを持っています
The Committee of Agriculture of this meeting and request has been sent out
今大会の農業委員会と要望書が出されています
But that is the next year's meeting
でもそれは来年の会議です
so i think probably not
だから多分違うと思う
because of the change of dynasty
王朝が変わったせいで
maybe next year again
たぶんまた来年
But I think we've planned
でも計画は立てたと思う
so there is doing
それでやっています
This is one about the bioeconomy
これはバイオエコノミーに関するものです
Another COA has planned a project called Productivity 4.0
別の COA は、Productivity 4.0 と呼ばれるプロジェクトを計画しています。
That is to put the so-called big data
それはいわゆるビッグデータを入れることです
And that modern manage management approach
そして、その最新の管理管理アプローチ
To get flower show agribusiness
フラワーショーアグリビジネスを獲得するには
so someone is doing it
だから誰かがやってる
so now you have a plan
これで計画ができました
someone has to do it
誰かがやらなければいけない
This is very important
これはとても重要です
yes i want not only in the middle
はい、真ん中だけでなく欲しいです
Central Plains I want to be in college at COA
セントラル・プレーンズ COA の大学に通いたいです
there are still many scientists
まだ科学者がたくさんいます
and these executives
そしてこの幹部たち
everybody wants to do something
誰もが何かをしたいと思っています
that's why i say this
だから私はこれを言います
That's why I'm still quite optimistic
だからこそ私はまだかなり楽観的だ
I am optimistic by nature
私は本質的に楽観的です
So I think there will still be improvement
なので、まだまだ改善はあると思います
Li En is
リー・エンは
it's okay lee
大丈夫だよリー
Thanks
ありがとう
ok please
はい、お願いします
that just mentioned
それは今言った
We have some that can be biologically controlled
生物学的に制御できるものもある
When producing organisms to resist that germ
その細菌に抵抗する微生物を作り出すとき
that could reduce our use of pesticides
それは農薬の使用を減らすことができる
So how to do a promotion of these
では、これらのプロモーションをどのように行うか
And how to study the classics
そして古典を勉強する方法
if go for it
頑張れば
This may be a major feature we are facing
これは私たちが直面している大きな特徴かもしれません
Yes, this is actually ours should be from last year
はい、これは実際には私たちのもので、昨年のものであるはずです
It is the Council of Agriculture that plans our country's major agricultural research topic in the next ten years
今後10年間の我が国の主要な農業研究課題を計画するのは農業評議会である
One is the time of living beings and the other is the time of living beings
一つは生き物の時間、もう一つは生き物の時間
If you go back and read the report from last year
昨年のレポートを読み返してみると
So there will probably be more or less the experience of this aspect coming out.
ですから、この側面の経験は多かれ少なかれ出てくるでしょう。
In fact, many people in Taiwan are now doing so-called biological research
実際、台湾では現在、多くの人がいわゆる生物学的研究を行っています。
But it's a pity it's only half done
でもまだ半分しか終わってないのが残念
Because they often find useful bacteria
有用な細菌を見つけることが多いため
In fact, if you go to Taiwan carefully to find out about that
実はそれをよく知るために台湾に行ってみると
Because Mr. Wu and I are in charge of the so-called national research program in Taiwan.
というのは、呉さんと私は台湾のいわゆる国家研究プログラムを担当しているからです。
Then you know that there are many useful bacteria
そうすれば、有用な細菌がたくさんいることがわかります
also know what he can cure
彼が何を治療できるかも知っている
but can't leave the country
でも出国できない
because they didn't make it like we did
彼らは私たちのようにはできなかったから
That is to say, what are you like other than identification?
つまり、アイデンティティ以外にあなたは何ですか？
The structure of this compound
この化合物の構造
You also need to know how it is synthesized
どのように合成されるのかも知る必要があります
you need to know under what circumstances
どのような状況で起こるかを知る必要があります
it can be mass produced
大量生産できる
because the lotus i visited
私が訪れた蓮なので
It is the great merchant of the biological order
それは生物界の大商人です
It has a ton or two of flower yeast sticks
花酵母スティックが1～2トン入っています
You have to be competitive
競争力を持たなければなりません
You just want a ton of production costs
莫大な制作費が欲しいだけだ
The training machine costs 1,400 Taiwan dollars
トレーニングマシンの価格は1400台湾ドル
But we use in the lab
しかし、私たちは研究室で使用しています
probably more than ten thousand yuan
おそらく1万元以上
that is to say if you want a ton
つまり、1トン欲しいなら
so this down
それでこれを下に
That is, you have to continue to do it
つまり、やり続けなければならないのです
Many teachers in Taiwan now have training
台湾では多くの教師が研修を受けています
But the problem is you don't know the mechanics of it
しかし問題は、そのメカニズムを知らないことです
you don't know what condition it is in
それがどのような状態にあるのかわかりません
This bacteria will produce the compound you want
このバクテリアはあなたが望む化合物を生成します
often the first generation is useful
多くの場合、第一世代が役に立ちます
Farmers go back to raise themselves
農家は戻って自分たちで育てます
or your company do it yourself
あるいはあなたの会社が自分でやるか
Often the second generation is useless
第二世代は役に立たないことが多い
So many big factories
大きな工場がたくさんある
Like Xinlong and Lianhua
シンロンとリアンファのように
they came out
彼らは出てきた
farmers scold
農民は叱る
Because you sell it seems to be useful for the first year
売ってるので1年目は使えそうです
useless in the second year
2年目では駄目
It's the comparison you want to do scientifically.
科学的に比較したいのです。
this is the most important
これが最も重要です
don't worry
心配しないで
If you know the mechanism
仕組みを知れば
what companies do you know
どのような会社を知っていますか
You can go abroad with Quality Control
品質管理をすれば海外にも行ける
So like our white jade archaea
私たちの白い翡翠の古細菌のように
The patent we are applying for now is
私たちが現在申請している特許は、
Mainland China America
中国本土 アメリカ
We just want to connect the Asian market with the US
私たちはアジア市場を米国と結び付けたいだけです
So back to Dean Li's words
ディーン・リーの言葉に戻りましょう
What does this government do?
この政府は何をしているのでしょうか？
help us open the way
道を開くのを手伝ってください
we have a foreign trade association
私たちには外国貿易協会があります
But they won't do it for farmers
しかし、彼らは農民のためにそれをしません
do this
これを行う
So this is where the government can focus
したがって、政府が集中できるのはここです
There are actually many details
実は細かい部分がたくさんあるんです
I didn't speak
話さなかった
I'm on this policy today
今日はこの方針に従っています
but many implementation aspects
しかし、実装上の多くの側面
You are still a place where the government can focus
あなたはまだ政府が集中できる場所です
still so much
まだそんなに
The key is to have money
鍵はお金を持つことです
So the first thing is to delete the 50 billion Laolong annuity
したがって、最初にすべきことは、500億の老龍年金を削除することです
your last question first
最初に最後の質問をしてください
Thanks
ありがとう
You mentioned a very serious problem in Taiwan
あなたは台湾における非常に深刻な問題について言及しました
It's food citizens' problem
それは食糧国民の問題です
Only 30% of myself
自分の30％だけ
this is very low
これは非常に低いです
Of course, improving the variety of Dao species is a very important way
もちろん、Dao 種の多様性を向上させることは非常に重要な方法です
Do you want to consider other than rice
お米以外も検討してみませんか
Species such as Potato
ジャガイモなどの種
or something else to increase Taiwan's food supply
あるいは台湾の食糧供給を増やすための何か他のこと
I remember when Wang Guoren was renting an apartment years ago
何年も前、王国仁がアパートを借りていたときのことを覚えています
he's doing it
彼はやってるよ
At that time, I was also developing this aspect
この側面も開発していました
have no idea
全く分かりません
Because now we eat more than just rice
だって今はご飯だけじゃないものを食べてるから
Some people eat very little rice now
今ではほとんどお米を食べない人もいます
changed to face
顔に変える
these grains
これらの穀物
Should it also be considered
それも考慮すべきか
these issues
これらの問題
Yes, this is actually 30 meters
はい、実際には30メートルです
is absolutely enough
絶対に十分です
I count 30%
30%だと思います
The heat we design
私たちがデザインする熱
70% are medium
70%は中程度
That is to say where the food comes from
つまり、食べ物はどこから来たのかというと、
70% are from outside
70％が外部からの参加者
So your most important thing to solve
したがって、解決すべき最も重要なことは
actually bones
実は骨
the Council of Agriculture
農業評議会
In fact, we in Taiwan had soybeans in the early days
実は台湾でも初期の頃から大豆があったのです。
that's in taiwan
それは台湾にあります
In fact, natural gas is not suitable for planting
実は天然ガスは植林には適さない
other bone species
他の骨種
rice is natural
お米は天然のもの
But neither soy nor sorghum
でも大豆もソルガムもダメ
but we have a pre-release for a while
しばらくプレリリースがありますが、
soybeans that can be grown in taiwan
台湾で栽培できる大豆
But you have to pre-produce new varieties
ただし、新しい品種を事前に生産する必要があります
To be able to really push out the plant
植物を本当に押し出すことができるようにするために
Yield, quality, everything should be good
収量、品質、すべてが良好である必要があります
Now the COA starts
COA が始まります
have this plan
この計画があります
They're the ones that are going to start pre-soybeans
彼らはプレ大豆を始める人たちです
That is to say, the varieties suitable for growing in Taiwan
つまり、台湾での栽培に適した品種です。
that so they go from there
それで彼らはそこから行きます
From the strict warehouse of the serious name
本格的な名前の厳格な倉庫から
There are some of this encouraging
こういう励みになるものもある
That strange wheat has
その奇妙な小麦は
so i want roommates here
だから私のルームメイトがここにいると思う
but not a lot of people here
でもここには人があまりいない
so maybe that means
だから多分それは意味する
roommate in need
困っているルームメイト
because if you really want to
なぜなら、本当にそうしたいなら
Don't root those fields
これらのフィールドをルート化しないでください
I think the most important thing is to
最も重要なことは、
produce other encouragement
他の励ましを生み出す
Even the so-called production so-called feed name
いわゆる本番のいわゆるフィード名でも
Because our greatest consumption
なぜなら私たちの最大の消費量は
In fact, you raise pigs and chickens
実際、豚や鶏を飼っているんですね
these things
これらの事
So you have to help Taiwan's food security
したがって、台湾の食糧安全保障を支援する必要があります
Everyone eats a bowl of rice every day
みんな毎日お茶碗一杯のご飯を食べます
It's all bowls
全部丼ですよ
Because it is a surprise demand
意外な要望なので
if you eat more
もっと食べたら
That means the price of rice will rise
つまり米の値段が上がる
So this is a
これは
you change your eating habits
あなたは食生活を変えます
the second is
2番目は
because you have less meat
肉が少ないから
Your bottom faces the bottom of this encouragement
この励ましの底を向いて
less inside
内側が少ない
The other one is the government's business
もう一つは政府の仕事です
just to start planting
植え始めるだけ
Even rice can be used as fodder
米も飼料として利用できる
So now the Agricultural Committee forbids us to say this
ですから、今、農業委員会は私たちがこれを言うことを禁じています。
because you talk about feed rice
飼料米の話をしているから。
He wonders why the rice you produce is used as feed
あなたが作ったお米がなぜ飼料として使われるのか疑問に思っています
He's afraid of you two getting together
彼はあなた達が一緒になるのを恐れています
So we have to think of a better one now
だから私たちは今より良いものを考えなければなりません
That is, if you use it as feed rice
つまり飼料米として使用する場合
You probably don't need that high quality
そこまでのクオリティは必要ないかもしれない
You can just go for a lot of that sort of thing
そういうことをたくさんやってもいいよ
So there are some scholars
だから学者もいるよ
Then we were doing it during the seminar
そしたらセミナー中にやってたんですよ
Several agricultural cover factories of the Council of Agriculture are slowly working on it
農業評議会のいくつかの農業用カバー工場が徐々に取り組んでいます。
But maybe there needs to be a country
でも、もしかしたら国が必要なのかもしれない
For example, another national project
たとえば、別の国家プロジェクト
plan this down
これを計画してください
Then I feel like it's not like it used to be
そうすると、以前とは違うような気がする
from the bottom one
一番下から
proposed by the researchers themselves
研究者自身が提案した
but you want a top down
でもあなたはトップダウンを望んでいます
That is to say, task marriage
つまりタスク婚
Which group of you do what kind of things
どのグループがどんなことをしているのか
do this
これを行う
That is to timely benefit
それはタイムリーな利益を得るということです
what we need in the next ten years
今後10年に必要なもの
Then mix this job down
次に、この仕事を混ぜ合わせます
then i think
それから私は思います
Taiwan can do it, absolutely no problem
台湾ならできる、全く問題ない
I will leave the last minute to Dean Li.
最後はディーン・リーに任せます。
Because I just challenged you to say that your two things are contradictory
なぜなら、私はあなたの 2 つのことが矛盾していると言ってあなたに挑戦しただけだからです
so i'm going to save you
だから私はあなたを救います
Thank you Dean Li
ありがとうディーン・リー
It is very important that the government takes the lead in people's participation
政府が国民の参加を率先して行うことが非常に重要です
because it didn't work
うまくいかなかったから
That's why I've been talking about the measurement points of Taiwan's farmers.
そういうわけで、私は台湾の農民の測定ポイントについて話してきました。
But you just talked about the food supply rate of 33%
しかし、先ほど食糧供給率33％の話をされましたね。
Near future
近い将来
When the world's food supply is not enough for everyone to eat
世界の食糧供給がすべての人が食べられるほど十分ではないとき
Taiwan, whose food supply rate is low, is the first to be hurt
食糧供給率が低い台湾が真っ先に被害を受ける
This is a problem that the government should take the lead in solving
これは政府が率先して解決すべき問題だ
So you were talking about problems like this farmhouse Hugh
つまり、あなたはこの農家のような問題について話していたのですね、ヒュー
Many of these issues are to be addressed by the government
これらの問題の多くは政府が対処する必要があります
We now say that the United States has a lot of pressure
今では米国には多大な圧力がかかっていると言われています
The markets of our agricultural products are all open
私たちの農産物の市場はすべて開かれています
But is our participation in this TPP good for farmers?
しかし、このTPPへの参加は農家にとって良いことなのでしょうか？
He did a lot of good things for the government, but it will be miserable in the future
彼は政府に多くの良いことをした、しかし将来は悲惨になるだろう
These things are good government for us
これらは私たちにとって良い政府です
representative of the good people
善良な人々の代表
this is a very important thing
これはとても重要なことです
That's why I just said I heard you make a rescue
だから私はあなたが救出をしたと聞いたと言いました
we didn't do that
私たちはそんなことはしませんでした
Only then did I bring up the highlights of many farmers in Taiwan
そのとき初めて、私は台湾の多くの農家のハイライトを取り上げました。
we are good
我々は良いです
The first point is done
最初のポイントが完了しました
we can have a good future
私たちは良い未来を手に入れることができます
so
それで
don't listen to your rescue
あなたの救いの言葉を聞かないでください
Thank you Li Yanze
リー・ヤンゼさん、ありがとう
thank you
ありがとう
Great speech thank you all
素晴らしいスピーチ、皆さんありがとうございました